<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sumter EMS Protocols</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <!-- Generic terms -->
    <string name="care_basic"><b>Basic Care</b></string>
    <string name="care_advanced"><b>Advanced Care</b></string>


    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
   

    <!-- param_Asthma -->
    <string name="title_activity_asthma"><b><u>ASTHMA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_asthma">
        <u>DO NOT DELAY TRANSPORT WAITING FOR TREATMENT RESPONSE</u> \n\n
            \t •  <b>Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity! Place patient in high-fowler\'s
                position or patients position of comfort. \n\n
            \t •  <b>BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30 times a
                minute will be ventilated with OCYGEN @ 15 LPM until advanced care is established. \n\n
            \t •  <b>Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses
                ). <u>Indications:</u> utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for complaint of dyspnea, and
                HR &lt;120. \n\n
            \t •  <b>Capnography: </b>Apply nasal cannual filter line \n\n
            \t •  <b>Albuterol: </b>2.5 mg via updraft, may repeat one additional time, if effective (1)
                . For Pediatric patients, administer <b>Albuterol </b>2.5 mg with 2 ml NS via blow-by technique \n\n
            \t •	<b>If the patient has already administered a home treatment of Albuterol 30 minutes or less
                prior to EMS arrival,   Go directly to Combined Updraft as listed below.</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg and <b>Atrovent</b> 0.5 mg <b>combined</b> via updraft. \n\n
                 \t\t i.	Do not administer Albuterol/Atrovent if heart rate > 150 or significant
                ventricular ectopy. If during use of either medication ventricular ectopy develops,
                is unresolved or becomes worse, discontinue the updraft immediately. \n\n
                 \t\t ii.	Consider in-line <b>Albuterol/Atrovent</b> with CPAP if patient\'s condition warrants. \n\n
            \t •  <b>Epinephrine:</b> 0.01 mg/kg of either 1:1000 SQ (adequate perfusion), or 1:10,000 IV (inadequate
                perfusion) (maximum total dose 0.3 mg). <b><i>Physician\'s Orders required for additional
                Epinephrine.</i></b> \n\n
                 \t\ti.	<b>Epinephrine</b>  should be administered as first medication while updraft
                    medications are being prepared if patient presents as unstable upon initial contact. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Solu-Medrol:</b> 2 mg/kg IVP (maximum total dose 125 mg). \n\n
            \t •	<b>Magnesium Sulfate:</b> 2 Grams in 100 ml IV over 10 minutes on a 10gtt set. \n\n
            \t •	<b>CPAP:</b> (refer to <i>CPAP Procedure Guideline</i> for indications). 7.5 - 8.5 cm/H2O
                PEEP setting. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety, etc.)
                refer to <i>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i> \n\n
    </string>

    <!-- param_Carbon Monoxide -->
    <string name="title_activity_carbon_monoxide">Carbon Monoxide</string>
    <string name="parameter_carbonmono">
    <b>Carbon Monoxide</b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b>
            \t •	Remove patient from source to a safe environment. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial medical care:</b> Permit no activity. Place patient in high-fowler\'s
                position or in patient\'s position of comfort. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Oxygen</b> 15 LPM via NRB with tight fitting mask \n\n
                \t\t <b>i</b> Document exact time oxygen therapy was initiated and relay to receiving
                    facility. Be aware, pulse oximetry may indicate a false positive. \n\n
            \t <b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30
                times a minute will be ventilated with <b>Oxygen</b> @ 15 LPM until advanced care is established. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b>
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>RAD-57 Monitor: Initial <u>Reading</u></b> \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.</b> 0 to 12: treat underlying symptoms \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.</b> 13 to 25: transport to local hospital \n\n
                \t\t <b>iii.</b> 26 and greater: transport to hyperbaric c \n\nhamber
            \t <b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate
                (severe anxiety, etc.) refer to <i>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Early coordination with receiving facility with Hyperbaric Chamber is
                essential</b> \n\n
            \t •	Transportation arrangements will be made in conjunction with Dispatch. The following
                destinations have access to <i>Hyperbaric Chambers: </i> \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.</b> Florida Hospital Orlando, Orlando \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.</b> Shands (UF Health) Hospital, Gainesville \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_copd">COPD</string>
    <string name="parameter_copd">
        <b><u>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I. BASIC CARE</b>  \n\n
            \t <b>• Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity. Place patient in high-fowler\'s position
                or in patient\'s position of comfort. \n\n
            \t <b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30 times
                a minute will be ventilated with <b>Oxygen</b> @ 15 LPM until advanced care is
                established. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses).
                <u>Indications:</u> utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for complaint of dyspnea, and HR
                &lt;120. \n\n
        <b>ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line, preferably before medications are
                administered if circumstances permit. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Albuterol:</b> 2.5 mg via updraft, repeat one time if effective. \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.</b>	Do not administer Albuterol/Atrovent if heart rate > 150 or significant
                    ventricular ectopy. If ventricular ectopy develops, is unresolved or becomes worse,
                    discontinue the updraft immediately. \n\n
            \t <b>•	If the patient has already administered a home treatment of Albuterol 30 minutes or less
                prior to EMS arrival, go directly to Combined Updraft as listed below. </b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg and <b>Atrovent</b> 0.5 mg <b>combined</b> via updraft. Consider
                in-line Albuterol/Atrovent with CPAP if patient\'s condition warrants. \n\n
            \t <b>•	CPAP:</b> Use 8 cm H2O PEEP setting. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Solu-Medrol:</b> 2 mg/kg IVP (maximum total dose 125 mg). \n\n
            \t <b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety,
                etc.) <i>refer to Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Difficult Airway / Facilitated Intubation-->
    <string name="title_activity_difficult_airway">DIFFICULT AIRWAY</string>
    <string name="parameter_diffairway">
        <b><u>DIFFICULT AIRWAY / FACILITATED INTUBATION</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	Indications </b>\n\n
	    Indicated for adult and pediatric patients (8 years of age or older) where ventilatory
        support and facilitated intubation and are required, to include both medical and trauma
        conditions. For pediatric patients under the age of 8, a Physician\'s Orders is required
        to administer Etomidate. This procedure guideline should be used as a replacement for those
        situations where Midazolam (Versed) was indicated for airway management. These situations
        include, but are not limited to: \n\n
            \t •	Asthma With Dyspnea \n
            \t •	COPD \n
            \t •	Carbon Monoxide Inhalation \n
            \t •	Foreign Body Airway Obstruction \n
            \t •	Pulmonary Edema \n
            \t •	Burns \n
            \t •	Head Injuries \n\n
        <b>II.	 General Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	This is not a one-person procedure. Assistance should be utilized to facilitate the
            best possible patient care. For trauma patients, use a second crewmember to maintain in-line
            C-spine at all times \n\n
            \t •	Basic Life Support procedures should always occur concurrently with the initial assessment
            of any patient with the potential of hypoxia. These should include oxygen (NRB or BVM), manual
            jaw thrust, use of nasal and oral airways, adequate suctioning, etc. For those patients requiring
            BVM ventilation, an adequate seal, along with Sellick\'s Maneuver, is imperative to provide adequate
            ventilation and reduce the occurrence of gastric distention. \n\n
            \t •	Always pre-oxygenate for a minimum of 1 full minute with 100%% oxygen, being careful not to
            hyperventilate at an excessive rate or force. \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is NOT spontaneously breathing or is breathing ineffectively, provide
            ventilatory support using a BVM with 100%% oxygen at a rate of 10-12 breaths per minute. \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is spontaneously breathing and breathing effectively, provide blow-by 100%%
            oxygen via NRB without overriding patient\'s ventilations, thereby reducing the risk of gastric
            distention.\n\n
            \t •	Gather and test all necessary equipment prior to the initial attempt. Prepare the
            cardiac monitor for capnography by attaching the EtCO2 Filter Line (see <i>Capnography
            Procedure Guideline</i>). \n\n
            \t •	Intubation attempts should not be initiated without cardiac and SpO2 monitoring in place,
            unless circumstances exist that preclude monitoring (very rare). A second crewmember should
            read and announce out loud the patient\'s heart rate and SPO2 continuously during intubation
            attempts. \n\n
            \t •	Attempt to open the mouth by scissors (thumb and forefinger) technique. Proceed with intubation
            as outlined in the INTUBATION- OROTRACHEAL PROCEDURE GUIDELINE. \n\n
            \t •	If sedation is necessary to facilitate intubation (intact gag reflex, unable to open the
            mouth due to trauma, if the jaw is clenched, etc.) return to BLS procedures and: \n\n
                \t\t 1.	Ensure best oxygenation and ventilation. \n\n
                \t\t 2.	Ensure a patent IV line exists. \n\n
                \t\t 3.	If BP > or = 100 mmHg systolic, administer 4 mg Midazolam IV Push over 30-60 seconds
                for sedation. If BP &lt; 100 mmHg systolic, skip Midazolam and proceed to Etomidate. \n\n
                \t\t 4.	Wait 2 minutes and assess for adequate sedation for intubation. If patient adequately
                sedated, proceed with intubation as outlined in the Intubation – Endotracheal Procedure Guideline. \n\n
                \t\t 5.	If patient requires additional sedation to facilitate intubation, administer 0.3 mg/kg Etomidate
                x 1 dose IVP over 30-60 seconds for sedation (Maximum single dose of 40 mg).\n\n
                \t\t 6.	Wait 2 minutes and assess for adequate sedation for intubation. Attempt a maximum of 2
                attempts to pass endotracheal tube through the vocal cords. \n\n
                \t\t 7.	During intubation attempts, monitor for signs of hypoxia (significant decrease in HR,
                SpO2 levels below 90%%, signs of ventricular ectopy, etc.). If hypoxia develops, stop all
                procedures and immediately ventilate the patient with 100%% oxygen. \n\n
                \t\t 8.	Following intubation, confirm proper tube placement by auscultating the gastric area
                and the lungs bilaterally. Attach the EtCO2 Filter Line hub to the endotracheal tube hub.
                Ventilate the patient with a BVM and watch for appropriate capnographic waveforms with each BVM
                ventilation. Record a monitor strip as capnographic verification of appropriate endotracheal tube
                placement. \n\n
                \t\t 9.	If intubation successful, progress to Section III: Successful Airway Procedure. \n\n
                \t\t 10.	If unable to intubate after Etomidate, progress to Section IV: Failed Airway Procedure. \n\n
        <b>III.	Successful Airway Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	Continuously monitor airway status to maintain intubation, adequate ventilation and adequate
            perfusion. Continue to monitor the capnographic waveforms throughout ventilations to confirm
            appropriate tube placement. Following any movement of the intubated patient to include at transfer
            of care, record a capnographic waveform strip to determine that there has not been ET tube
            dislodgment.\n\n
            \t •	If necessary to maintain sedation post-intubation and BP > or = 100 mmHg systolic, administer
            Midazolam in 2-mg increments IVP every 3-5 minutes (maximum total dosage is 10 mg). Diazepam may
            be substituted for Midazolam in 5 mg increments Slow IVP every 3-5 minutes (maximum total dosage
            is 20 mg).\n\n
            \t <b>•	If the need arises for additional post intubation sedation administer Fentanyl 0.5 mcg/kg
            as a loading dose followed by a Fentanyl drip at 2 mcg/min may be used for post intubation
            sedation refractory to Midazolam.</b>\n\n
        <b>IV.	Failed Airway Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	Revert to Basic Life Support airway procedures as described in Section II: General
            Procedure, ensuring adequate ventilation and oxygenation with 100%% oxygen. \n
            \t •	Keep the airway clear of secretions, blood and vomitus. \n
            \t •	If able to effectively ventilate the patient with a BVM, consider insertion of a
            King Airway and continue ventilations (refer to the <i>King Airway Insertion Procedure Guideline</i>). \n\n
            If attempts at ventilation fail, or ventilations fail to perfuse the patient with oxygen,
            immediately perform a Cricothyrotomy (refer to the <i>Cricothyrotomy- Surgical Procedure Guideline</i>). \n
    </string>

    <!-- param_Foreign Body Airway Obstruction -->
    <string name="title_activity_fbao">FBAO</string>
    <string name="parameter_fbao">
        <b><u>FOREIGN BODY AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>PARTIAL AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</b> \n\n
                \t\t•	Encourage the patient to continue spontaneous coughing and breathing efforts.
                    Do not interfere with the patient\'s own attempts to expel the foreign body,
                    but stay with the patient and monitor his or her condition. \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>Oxygen:</b> 15 LPM via NRB. \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
                \t\t•	Have equipment ready if patient condition deteriorates to COMPLETE AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION. \n\n
            \t <b>COMPLETE AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</b> \n\n
                \t\t<b>•	CONSCIOUS</b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	Adult / child: Abdominal thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t ii.	Pregnant / obese: Chest thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t iii.	Infant: Back blows and chest thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t iv.	Repeat until foreign object is expelled and airway is cleared OR patient
                        becomes unconscious. \n\n
                \t\t<b>•	UNCONSCIOUS</b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	<b>BVMR:</b> Open airway and attempt to ventilate. \n\n
                    \t\t\t ii.	Attempt to clear airway: \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 1.	Adult/child: Abdominal thrusts. \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 2.	Pregnant/obese: Chest thrusts. \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 3.	Infant: Back blows and chest thrusts. \n\n
                    \t\t\t iii.	Alternate attempts to ventilate with airway clearing techniques.
                        Once airway is cleared, support ventilations as needed with 100%% oxygen \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t•	If unable to clear airway with Basic Care and patient is unconscious: \n
            \t•	<b>Laryngoscope:</b> Visualize oropharynx and utilize Magill Forceps or suction as needed. \n
            \t•	<b>BVMR:</b> Open airway and attempt to ventilate. \n
            \t•	<b>Intubation:</b> If unable to ventilate and foreign object not visible with Laryngoscope. If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety, etc.) refer to Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline \n
            \t•	<b>Cricothyrotomy:</b> If unable to ventilate effectively after above attempts. \n\n
        <b>III.	Initial Medical Care:</b> establish after airway is secured. \n\n
        <b>NOTE: All patients should be encouraged to seek medical attention even
            if airway is cleared on scene.</b> \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Pulomary Edema-->
    <string name="title_activity_pe">Pulmonary Edema</string>
    <string name="parameter_pe">
        <b><u>PULMONARY EDEMA</u></b> \n\n
            \t If Pulse &lt; 60 and systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, refer to Bradycardia &amp; A.V.
                Blocks Clinical Care Guideline. \n
            \t If systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, refer to Shock (Non-Fluid Loss) Clinical Care Guideline. \n
            \t If systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, use treatment algorithm listed below: \n\n\n
        <b>BASIC CARE</b>
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity! Place patient in high-fowler\ʼs position
                or in patient\'s position of comfort. \n\n
            \t <b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations &lt; 10 or > 30 times a minute will
                be ventilated with Oxygen @ 15 LPM NRB until advanced care is established. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses).
                Indications: utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for dyspnea and HR &lt; 120. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL, repeat every 5 minutes if BP > 100 mmHg. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Do not administer NTG if the patient has taken phosphodiesterase (PDE) inhibitors
                    including: Viagra (sildenafil), Levitra (vardenafil) or Cialis (tadalafil) within
                    past 24 hours. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin Paste:</b> 1 inch applied transdermal. \n\n
            \t <b>•	CPAP:</b> (refer to CPAP Procedure Guideline for indications). Use the 10 cm H2O
                setting. For patients with a history of COPD or Asthma, use 8cm H2O PEEP setting for CPAP. \n\n
            \t •	If patient has chest pain, Fentanyl 1 mcg/kg, repeat every 5 minutes \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fentanyl</b> 1 mcg/kg IVP. If pain persists, after five minutes repeat dose once
                (maximum total dose 2 mcg/kg). \n\n
                \t\t *   *Do not administer in pregnant or possible pregnant patients. \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	<b>Physician\'s Orders</b> required for additional Morphine Sulfate.\n\n
            \t <b>•	Physician\ʼs Orders:</b> If the patient presents with fluid overload (rales, pitting edema > 2+),
                \t\t i.	<b>Bumetanide</b> 1 mg IVP for patients &lt; 70 kg or 2 mg IVP
            for patients > 70 kg.
            \t <b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety,
                etc.) refer to <u>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline</u>.
    </string>

    <!--param_Acute Coronary Syndrome-->
    <string name="title_acs">Acute Coronary SyndromePulmonary Edema</string>
    <string name="parameter_acs">
        <b><u>ACUTE CORONARY SYDROME</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity. Place patient in their
                position of comfort. If BP &lt; 90 mmHg, encourage the patient to lie supine. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Prescription Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL every 5 minutes (maximum 3 total doses).
                Indications: utilize patient\'s prescribed NTG for cardiac-related chest discomfort and BP
                > 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative change
                in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Aspirin:</b> 324 mg PO (chew and swallow). \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL, repeat every 5 minutes if BP > 90 mmHg. \n\n
                \t\t i.	    Give strong consideration to IV insertion prior to administration of Nitroglycerin. \n
                \t\t ii.	Do not administer NTG if the patient has taken phosphodiesterase (PDE) inhibitors
                    including: Viagra (sildenafil), Levitra (vardenafil) or Cialis (tadalafil) within past 24
                    hours. \n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin Paste:</b> 1 inch applied transdermal. \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.	Fentanyl</b> 1mcg/kg IVP repeat every 5 minutes (Fentanyl 1 mcg/kg IVP.
                    If pain persists, after five minutes repeat dose once \n
                \t\t (maximum total dose 2 mcg/kg).* \n\n
                \t\t *Do not administer in pregnant or possible pregnant patients. \n\n
                \t\t i.	<b>Physician\'s Orders</b> <i>required for additional Fentanyl.</i> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Ondansetron:</b> 4 mg slow IVP for nausea and vomiting. May give IM if no IV. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Second IV:</b> Establish a second IV of NS at KVO or Saline-lock. Indications: STEMI,
                shock, widespread ST depression, or any medication by drip. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Dysrhythmias:</b> If dysrhythmias are noted, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care
                Guideline</i> for specific treatments. \n\n
        III.	<b>Determine Transport Destination:</b> refer to <i>Transport – Cardiac Administrative
            Policy</i>. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Asystole/PEA-->
    <string name="title_activity_asystole">Asystole/PEA</string>
    <string name="parameter_asystole">
        <b><u>ASYSTOLE – PEA</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	ABCD:</b> Perform appropriate action following American Heart Association (AHA)
                CPR Guidelines. \n\n
            \t •	Follow <i>End of Life Administrative Policy</i>, as necessary. \n\n
            \t •	If arrest > 4 minutes: perform 2-minutes of CPR prior to assessing rhythm. \n\n
            \t •	If arrest &lt; 4 minutes or witnessed arrest: assess rhythm. \n\n
            \t •	Reassess rhythm after every 2 minute period of CPR; assess radial pulse if organized rhythm,
                do not exceed 10 seconds. If no radial pulse or unsure, resume CPR \n\n
                \t\t i.	If using an AED, follow the manufacturer\'s prompts for cardiac arrest management.\n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Vascular Access:</b> IV or IO. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Epinephrine:</b> 1 mg 1:10,000 IVP/IO followed by 10ml NS bolus. Repeat every 3 - 5
                minutes of continued arrest \n\n
            \t <b>•	Advanced Airway</b> (endotracheal tube, King Tube). Search for and treat 6 H\'s &amp; 5 T\'s. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Reconfirm placement after repositioning or moving patient. Administer 8-10
                    breaths/minute via BVM; avoid hyperventilation.\n\n
            \t <b>•	Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP/IO or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes (maximum total
                dose 10 mg). Indications: combative post-resuscitation patients. Use with caution
                for systolic BP &lt; 100 mmHg.
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Pulomary Edema-->
    <string name="title_activity_bradycardia">Bradycardia</string>
    <string name="parameter_bradycardia">
        <b><u>BRADYCARDIA</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. Place patient in
            Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative change
                in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached \n\n
            \t <b>•	Monitor and Observe</b> closely for changes in patients with adequate perfusion. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Non-Symptomatic</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	Apply Transcutaneous Pacer on standby. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Symptomatic</b> \n\n
                \t\t <b><u>i.	Sinus Bradycardia</u></b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>1.	Atropine Sulfate:</b> 0.5 mg IVP, repeat every 3 - 5 minutes (maximum
                    total dose 3 mg). \n\n
                \t\t <b><u>ii.	2nd or 3rd Degree Block</u></b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>1.	Sedation: Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes
                        (maximum total dose 10 mg). \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>2.	Transcutaneous Pacing:</b> 60 BPM and increase mA from minimum setting until
                        consistent electrical capture is achieved. Verify mechanical capture and increase mA
                        by 10 for safety margin. Refer to <i>Transcutaneous Pacing Procedure Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Dopamine:</b> 5 mcg/kg/min IV drip, reassess every 5 minutes for patient response and
                titrate in 5 mcg/kg/min increments (max total dose 20 mcg/kg/min). \n\n
                /t/t <b>i.	Indications:</b> unstable patient (inadequate perfusion) with verified pulse
                    rate &lt; 60 unresponsive to Atropine or TCP. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Narrow Complex Tachycardia - irregular-->
    <string name="title_activity_narrowtach_irreg">Narrow Complex Tachycardia - Irregular</string>
    <string name="parameter_narrowtach_irreg">
        <b><u>NARROW COMPLEX TACHYCARDIA – IRREGULAR</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. Place
                patient in Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative
                change in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Vagal Maneuvers:</b> perform Valsalva maneuver or apply cool moisture to face. \n\n
            \t •	If patient has a history of WPW, refer to <i>Wide Complex Tachycardia Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t <b><u>STABLE</u></b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS Lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Check blood glucose level:</b> if blood glucose is &lt; 60 or > 250, also refer to
                Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Administer a fluid bolus 250 ml of NS. Continue IV infusion KVO. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Diltiazem:</b>  15 mg slow IVP over 2 minutes \n\n
            \t •<b>Diltiazem:</b>	 25 mg slow IVP over 2 minutes, if rhythm unchanged. \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG</b> after conversion \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>.\n\n
            \t <b><u>UNSTABLE – Systolic BP &lt; 90 mm Hg, AMS, Cardiac-focused chest pain</u></b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached, if rapidly possible. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Consider sedation: Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes (max dose 10 mg) \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 100 joules \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Consider fluid bolus 250 ml of NS if no response to cardioversion. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 200 joules \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Diltiazem:</b> 15 mg IV over 2 minutes \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 300 joules \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 360 joules \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG</b> after conversion \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Narrow Complex Tachycardia - regular-->
    <string name="title_activity_narrowtach_reg">Narrow Complex Tachycardia - Regular</string>
    <string name="parameter_narrowtach_reg">
        <b><u>NARROW COMPLEX TACHYCARDIA – REGULAR</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort.
                Place patient in Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative
                    change in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Vagal Maneuvers:</b> perform Valsalva maneuver or apply cool moisture to face. \n\n
            \t <b><u>STABLE</u></b>
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Check blood glucose level:</b> if blood glucose is &lt; 60 or > 250, also refer
                to Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Administer a fluid bolus 250 ml of NS. Continue IV infusion KVO. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Adenosine:</b> 12 mg rapid IVP/IO. If no conversion, \n\n
            \t <b>•	Adenosine:</b> 12 mg rapid IVP/IO \n\n
            \t <u>Indication:</u> stable patients with regular narrow-complex tachycardia (PSVT, AT).
            \t •	If rhythm converts briefly to reveal an irregular rhythm, refer to <i>Narrow Complex
                Tachycardia – Irregular Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t •	Consider possible causes of dysrhythmia (6 H\'s and 6 T\'s). \n\n
            \t •	If patient condition deteriorates, refer to <b>UNSTABLE</b> treatment. \n\n
            \t •	<b><u>Physician Consult</u></b> for alternative treatments if above antiarrhythmic
                agents are unsuccessful in rhythm conversion or rate control. \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post
                Resuscitation Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t <b><u>UNSTABLE</u></b> – Systolic BP &lt; 90 mm Hg, AMS, cardiac-focused chest pain \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached, if rapidly possible. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Consider Sedation: Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes
                (maximum total dose 10 mg). \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 100 joules.
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Consider fluid bolus 250 ml of NS if no response to cardioversion
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 200 joules
            \t •	If no response administer 12mg of <b>Adenosine</b>
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 300 joules
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 360 joules
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>.
    </string>

    <!--param_Narrow Complex Tachycardia - irregular-->
    <string name="title_activity_rosc">Post Resuscitation/ROSC</string>
    <string name="parameter_rosc">
        <b><u>POST RESUSCITATION MANAGEMENT</u></b> \n\n
        <b><u>INDICATIONS</u></b> \n\n
            \t •	POST CARDIAC ARREST WITH RETURN OF CIRCULATION \n\n
            \t •	PRESENCE OF A PALPABLE BLOOD PRESSURE \n\n
            \t •	MENTAL STATUS MAY VARY \n\n
        <b><u>ADVANCED CARE</u></b> \n\n
            \t •	Continue treatment per appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline and presumed
                underlying cause</i>. \n\n
            \t •	Airway management to include oxygen and ventilation support. Do not
                over-ventilate. \n\n
            \t •	Maintain Pulse oximetry to 94% or greater \n\n
            \t •	Maintain Capnography between 35 and 45 mm Hg \n\n
            \t •	Monitor cardiac rhythm for changes and treat per appropriate Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	12 Lead EKG: Monitor for possible STEMI alert criteria. \n\n
            \t •	Treat hypotension (systolic BP &lt; 90 mm Hg) with IV fluids and Dopamine per appropriate
                Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	If patient remains unresponsive refer to Induced Hypothermia Procedure Guideline. \n\n


    </string>

    <!--VAD-->
    <string name="title_activity_vad">VAD</string>
    <string name="parameter_vad">
        <b><u>VENTRICULAR ASSISTANCE DEVICE</u></b> \n\n
        This Appendix applies to the management of patients who have a ventricular assist device (VAD)
        also referred to a left ventricular assist device (LVAD) implanted. The VAD is a mechanical pump
        used to support the heart\’s pumping function and positive blood flow on individuals who have severe
        heart failure. \n\n
        <b>INITIAL MEDICAL CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Perform initial assessment: vital signs, oxygen saturation, pre-treatment 12-Lead ECG,
                focused history (SAMPLE, OPQRST), and physical exam. Inquire if the patient has an old ECG. \n\n
                \t\t o	Provide OXYGEN @ 100% via NRB mask or assist ventilations/oxygenation as indicated. \n\n
            \t •	Listen to heart sounds. The heart sounds may be faint. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Check for a functioning VAD:</b> These devices are usually implanted below the heart
                    in the abdominal cavity area. Use a stethoscope to listen for constant humming or whirling
                    sound. This sound confirms the VAD is functioning. \n\n
                \t\t o	The nature of the VAD function provides positive constant flow (it is a centrifugal
                    pump) therefore a <b>pulse may not be palpable</b> in these patients. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Blood Pressure:</b> A manual blood pressure may not be obtainable. An automated blood
                    pressure monitoring device may provide a reading with a narrow pulse pressure. \n\n
                \t\t o	Treatment of these patients must be based on the mean arterial pressure (MAP). The normal
                    MAP should be between 60 and 90 mm/Hg. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Pulse Oximetry:</b> These readings may not be accurate due to the continuous flow provided
                    by the VAD. \n\n
                \t\t o	Monitor side capnography for ventilation and oxygenation effectiveness. \n\n
        <b>UNRESPONSIVE PATIENT</b> \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is unresponsive to stimuli: \n\n
                \t\t o	Open the airway and ventilate/oxygenate as necessary. \n\n
                \t\t o	Obtain a blood glucose level and treat per Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia
                    Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	Listen for a functioning VAD by auscultating over the abdomen. \n\n
                \t\t o	If the VAD has a whirling sound it is properly functioning. \n\n
                \t\t o	<b>DO NOT PERFORM CPR!</b> \n\n
            \t 	A VAD or LVAD is surgically implanted to the left ventricle. External cardiac compressions
                may dislodge the VAD causing death. \n\n
            \t •	If the VAD is silent have the caregiver or family member check the device external pump
                controller and power supply. \n\n
                \t\t o	<b>LISTEN TO THE CAREGIVER!</b> These individuals are experts in these devices and
                    know/understand how to operate and troubleshoot the system. \n\n
                \t\t o	VAD patients are instructed to always have a backup bag with 2 charged batteries
                    and a second pump controller. \n\n
                \t\t o	Contact the VAD coordinator listed on the patient’s information card. \n\n
            \t•	If the VAD is inoperative despite troubleshooting and battery replacement, then CPR
                is indicated as per cardiac arrest parameter. \n\n

        <b>RESPONSIVE PATIENT:</b> \n\n
            \t •	Perform a subjective interview to determine chief complaint and history of present illness. \n\n
            \t •	Monitor ECG and obtain a 12 lead ECG if chest pain, ischemic symptoms, shortness of breath or
                weakness is reported. \n\n
                \t\t o	Any cardiac dysrhythmias must be treated per the appropriate practice parameter. \n\n
                \t\t o	If electrical therapy is indicated on a conscious patient, the patient may be sedated
                    (time permitting) as per parameter. \n\n
            \t•	Establish IV access and provide fluid resuscitation as indicated based on patient\’s condition
                and hydration status. \n\n
            \t•	Assess for any other concurrent medical conditions or symptoms and treat per the appropriate
                parameter. \n\n

        <b>TRANSPORT OF PATIENT:</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	ALL VAD patients with cardiac, respiratory, neurological or infectious disease complaints
                must be transported to the VAD center.</b> \n\n
                \t\t o	Florida Hospital Orlando and UF Health Shands are the only local approved VAD centers. \n\n
                \t\t o	Contact the VAD coordinator as soon as possible and notify them of the transport. \n\n
            \t •	VAD patients presenting with minor complaints may be transported to any receiving facility
                as long as they have their backup batteries and equipment with the patient. \n\n
                \t\t o	These complaints include, but are not limited to: \n\n
            \t 	Minor sprains, strains or orthopedic injuries \n\n
            \t 	Hypoglycemia without severe signs or symptoms \n\n
            \t 	Isolated extremity lacerations \n\n
            \t •	Don’t forget the family member/caregiver! \n\n
                \t\t o	The family member/caregiver must <b>ACCOMPANY</b> the patient in the ambulance. \n\n
                \t\t o	These individuals have intimate knowledge of the patient\’s condition, the system and
                    usually have legal authority to sign on behalf of the patient. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Bring all VAD equipment, backup bags, charger and batteries with the patient!</b> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Ventricular Fibrillation & Pulseless VTACNarrow Complex Tachycardia - irregular-->
    <string name="title_activity_vfib">VFib &amp; Puleless VTAC</string>
    <string name="parameter_vfib">
        <b><u>VENTRICULAR FIBRILLATION &amp; PULSELESS V-TACH</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Check for responsiveness - Shake and shout, Pain stimulation \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Initiate CCR</b> (Cardio-Cerebral Resuscitation) – Continuous chest
                compressions \n\n
                \t\t i.	At least 100 compressions per minute with at least a 2 inch compression depth \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Continue CCR for two minutes \n\n
            \t •	Place “Quick Combo Pads” (Defibrillation Pads) \n\n
            \t <b>•	Defibrillate</b> initially at 200 joules or follow directions from AED \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.	Second Defibrillation setting should be at 300 joules</b> \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.	All subsequent defibrillations should be at 360 joules</b> \n\n
            \t •	Immediately following the shock, return to 2-minutes of CCR.  It is imperative that
                there be no break in the compressions other than the second or two that it takes to
                change out rescuers performing CCR. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE:</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Venous Access:</b>  If possible, while CCR is being performed, establish a large-bore
                IV/IO of NS \n\n
            \t <b>•	Epinephrine:</b>  1 mg of 1:10,000 IVP/IO.  Repeat every 3-5 minutes of continued arrest.
                Medication should be administered while CCR is in progress. Follow with 10ml NS bolus \n\n
            \t <b>•	Antiarrhythmic Agents:</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	Amiodarone:  300 mg IVP/IO followed by 10ml NS bolus. Repeat 150 mg once, if
                    necessary. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Magnesium Sulfate:  2 Gram mixed in 10 ml NS slow IVP/IO over 5 minutes.
                    Repeat x 1 dose (max total dose of 2 Grams). Indications:  Torsade’s de Pointes or
                    the maximum dose of 450 mg of amiodarone has been administered and the patient still
                    presents in ventricular fibrillation or pulseless ventricular tachycardia. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Airway:</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	OPA:  Place an OPA \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Place the patient on oxygen with a non-rebreather mask set at 10-12 L/min. \n\n
                \t\t Precaution:  Be prepared to remove the OPA and NRBM if the patient vomits.  Have the
                    suction unit prepared and ready. \n\n
                \t\t iii.	Endotracheal Intubation / King Tube Insertion:  If there is a ROSC or if time
                    permits and there is no interruption of CCR, the NRBM may be replaced by an ET or King
                    and high-liter flow O2.  If a BVM is used, the patient should be bagged using a rate of
                    6-8 one-handed ventilations per minute only. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Analysis:</b>  Following the post-shock 2 minutes of CCR, either allow the AED to
                    analyze the rhythm or if using a manual defibrillator, briefly analyze the rhythm. \n\n
                \t\t i.	If the rhythm continues as Ventricular Fibrillation or Pulseless Ventricular
                    Tachycardia, \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>1.	Defibrillate</b> again at 360-joules.  Continue the “Shock – Post-Shock”
                    cycle as long as he patient remains in VF or pulseless VT. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	If the patient has a return of spontaneous circulation (palpable pulses,
                    respirations, blood pressure), \n\n
                    \t\t\t 1.	Place the ET or King as previously discussed if the patient will tolerate
                        same or utilize a non-rebreather mask at 10-12 L/min and then initiate… \n\n
            \t <b>•	Post Conversion Drip Therapy:</b>
                \t\t <b>i.	Amiodarone:</b>  150 mg IV/IO bolus followed by an Amiodarone 150 mg IV/IO drip
                    (over 10 minutes). \n\n
                    \t\t\t 1.	150 mg in 100 ml D5W: 150 mg/10 min = 15.0 mg/min (100gtts/min on 10gtt IV
                        set or 600ml/h on IV pump). \n\n
                    \t\t\t 2.	If rhythm converts prior to administration of an antiarrhythmic agent, administer
                        the bolus and the drip as above. \n\n
                    \t\t\t 3.	If any Amiodarone has been administered via bolus during the resuscitative
                        efforts, administer only the Amiodarone drip as above. \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.	Magnesium Sulfate:</b>  2G IV/IO drip (over 1 hour) \n\n
                    \t\t\t 1.	2G in 250 ml D5W: 2 G/hr. =33.4mg/min (250gtts/min on 60gtt IV set or 250ml/hr.
                        on IV pump) \n\n
                    \t\t\t 2.	Indications: Torsade’s de pointes \n\n
                \t\t <b>iii.	Midazolam:</b>  2 mg IV/IO or Intra-Nasal.  Repeat every 3-5 minutes (max total
                    dose of 10 mg). Indications:  Combative, post-resuscitation patients. Use with caution in
                    presence of hypotension (BP &lt; 90 mmHg \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_-->
    <string name="title_activity_wide_comples">Wide Complex Tachycardia -Irregular</string>
    <string name="parameter_wide_complex">
        <b><u>WIDE COMPLEX TACHYCARDIA</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. Place patient
                in Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mm/Hg systolic. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative change
                in condition and/or every 15 minutes.\n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS Lock attached \n\n
            \t <b>STABLE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Monitor and Observe</b> closely for changes in patients with adequate perfusion. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Amiodarone</b> 150 mg IV drip (over 10 minutes). Indications: stable patients with
                regular wide-complex tachycardia \n\n
            \t <b>•	Magnesium Sulfate</b> 2G in 10 ml NS Slow IV (over 5 minutes), repeat x 1 dose
                (max total dose 2G). Indications: torsade\’s de pointes.  \n\n
            \t <b>•	Physician\ʼs Consult:</b> for alternative treatments if above antiarrhythmic agents are
                unsuccessful in rhythm conversion or rate control.  \n\n
            \t <b>UNSTABLE</b>  \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 100 J. <u>Indications:</u> unstable patients with inadequate
                perfusion. Consider pre-medication with <b>Midazolam:</b> 2 mg IV or Intra-Nasal, repeat
                every 3-5 minutes until adequate relaxation sedation is achieved prior to procedure (
                max total dosage is 10 mg). Use <b>Midazolam</b> with caution in the presence of hypotension
                (BP &lt; 100 mmHg). \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 200 J \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Amiodarone</b> 150mg IV Bolus \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 300 J \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 360 J \n\n
            \t •	Post-Conversion Maintenance Therapy: \n\n
                \t\t i.	<b>Amiodarone</b> 150 mg IV drip (over 10 minutes) \n\n
                    \t\t\t <u>Indications:</u> If rhythm converts prior to antiarrhythmic agent \n\n
                \t\t ii.	<b>Magnesium Sulfate</b> IV drip of 2 Gram/hr. \n\n
                    \t\t\t <u>Indications:</u> If <b>Magnesium</b> converts torsade\’s de pointes \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
        <b><u>III.	NOTES:</u></b> \n\n
            \t <b>1.	Amiodarone drip:</b> (150 mg in 100 ml NS) \n\n
                \t\t 150 mg/10 min = 15.0 mg/min (100gtts/min on 10gtt IV set or 600 ml/h on IV pump) \n\n
            \t <b>2.	Magnesium Sulfate drip:</b> (2G in 250 ml D5W) \n\n
                \t\t 2G/hr = 33.4 mg/min (250gtts/min on 60gtt IV set or 250 ml/hr on IV pump \n\n\n
    </string>

</resources>
