<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sumter EMS Protocols</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <!-- Generic terms -->
    <string name="care_basic"><b>Basic Care</b></string>
    <string name="care_advanced"><b>Advanced Care</b></string>


    <!-- param_Asthma -->
    <string name="title_activity_asthma"><b><u>Asthma</u></b></string>
    <string name="title_activity_asthma_sub"><u>DO NOT DELAY TRANSPORT WAITING FOR TREATMENT RESPONSE</u></string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_bc1">•  <b>Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity! Place patient in high-fowler\'s
        position or patients position of comfort. </string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_bc2">•  <b>BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30 times a
        minute will be ventilated with OCYGEN @ 15 LPM until advanced care is established.</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_bc3">•  <b>Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses
        ). <u>Indications:</u> utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for complaint of dyspnea, and HR &lt;120. </string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac1">•  <b>Capnography: </b>Apply nasal cannual filter line</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac2">•  <b>Albuterol: </b>2.5 mg via updraft, may repeat one additional time, if effective (1)
        . For Pediatric patients, administer <b>Albuterol </b>2.5 mg with 2 ml NS via blow-by technique</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac3">•	<b>If the patient has already administered a home treatment of Albuterol 30 minutes or less
        prior to EMS arrival,   Go directly to Combined Updraft as listed below.</b></string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac4">•	<b>Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg and <b>Atrovent</b> 0.5 mg <b>combined</b> via updraft.</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac5">     i.	Do not administer Albuterol/Atrovent if heart rate > 150 or significant
        ventricular ectopy. If during use of either medication ventricular ectopy develops, is unresolved or becomes
        worse, discontinue the updraft immediately.</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac6">     ii.	Consider in-line <b>Albuterol/Atrovent</b> with CPAP if patient\'s condition warrants.</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac7">•  	<b>Epinephrine:</b> 0.01 mg/kg of either 1:1000 SQ (adequate perfusion), or 1:10,000 IV (inadequate
        perfusion) (maximum total dose 0.3 mg). <b><i>Physician\'s Orders required for additional Epinephrine.</i></b></string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac8">     i.	<b>Epinephrine</b>  should be administered as first medication while updraft
        medications are being prepared if patient presents as unstable upon initial contact.</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac9">•	<b>Solu-Medrol:</b> 2 mg/kg IVP (maximum total dose 125 mg).</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac10">•	<b>Magnesium Sulfate:</b> 2 Grams in 100 ml IV over 10 minutes on a 10gtt set.</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac11">•	<b>CPAP:</b> (refer to <i>CPAP Procedure Guideline</i> for indications).
        7.5 - 8.5 cm/H2O PEEP setting.</string>
    <string name="tv_asthma_ac12">•	<b>Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety, etc.)
        refer to <i>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i></string>

    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="title_activity_asthma2">AsthmaActivity2</string>


    <!-- param_Carbon Monoxide -->
    <string name="title_activity_carbon_monoxide">Carbon Monoxide</string>
    <string name="title_activity_carbonmono"><b>Carbon Monoxide</b></string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_bc1">•	Remove patient from source to a safe environment.</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_bc2"><b>•	Initial medical care:</b> Permit no activity. Place patient in high-fowler\'s
        position or in patient\'s position of comfort.</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_bc3"><b>•	Oxygen</b> 15 LPM via NRB with tight fitting mask</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_bc4"><b>i</b> Document exact time oxygen therapy was initiated and relay to receiving
        facility. Be aware, pulse oximetry may indicate a false positive.</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_bc5"><b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30
        times a minute will be ventilated with <b>Oxygen</b> @ 15 LPM until advanced care is established.</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac1"><b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line.</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac2"><b>RAD-57 Monitor: Initial <u>Reading</u></b></string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac3"><b>i.</b> 0 to 12: treat underlying symptoms</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac4"><b>ii.</b> 13 to 25: transport to local hospital</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac5"><b>iii.</b> 26 and greater: transport to hyperbaric chamber</string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac6"><b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate
        (severe anxiety, etc.) refer to <i>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i></string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac7"><b>•	Early coordination with receiving facility with Hyperbaric Chamber is
        essential</b></string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac8">•	Transportation arrangements will be made in conjunction with Dispatch.
        The following destinations have access to <i>Hyperbaric Chambers: </i></string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac9"><b>i.</b> Florida Hospital Orlando, Orlando </string>
    <string name="tv_carbonmono_ac10"><b>ii.</b> Shands (UF Health) Hospital, Gainesville </string>


    <string name="title_activity_copd">COPD</string>
    <string name="copd_header"><b><u>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</u></b></string>
    <string name="tv_copd_bc"><b>I. BASIC CARE</b></string>
    <string name="tv_copd_bc1"><b>• Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity. Place
        patient in high-fowler\'s position or in patient\'s position of comfort.</string>
    <string name="tv_copd_bc2"><b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater
        than 30 times a minute will be ventilated with <b>Oxygen</b> @ 15 LPM until advanced care is established.</string>
    <string name="tv_copd_bc3"><b>•	Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses). Indications:
        utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for complaint of dyspnea, and HR &lt;120.</string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac"><b>ADVANCED CARE</b></string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac1"><b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line, preferably before
        medications are administered if circumstances permit. </string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac2"><b>•	Albuterol:</b> 2.5 mg via updraft, repeat one time if effective. </string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac3"><b>i.</b>	Do not administer Albuterol/Atrovent if heart rate > 150 or significant ventricular
        ectopy. If ventricular ectopy develops, is unresolved or becomes worse, discontinue the updraft immediately. </string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac4"><b>•	If the patient has already administered a home treatment of Albuterol 30 minutes or less
        prior to EMS arrival,   Go directly to Combined Updraft as listed below. </b></string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac5"><b>•	Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg and <b>Atrovent</b> 0.5 mg <b>combined</b> via updraft.
        Consider in-line Albuterol/Atrovent with CPAP if patient\'s condition warrants. </string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac6"><b>•	CPAP:</b> Use 8 cm H2O PEEP setting. </string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac7"><b>•	Solu-Medrol:</b> 2 mg/kg IVP (maximum total dose 125 mg). </string>
    <string name="tv_copd_ac8"><b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate
        (severe anxiety, etc.) <i>refer to Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i></string>

    <!--param_Difficult Airway / Facilitated Intubation-->
    <string name="title_activity_difficult_airway">DIFFICULT AIRWAY</string>
    <string name="parameter_diffairway">
        <b><u>DIFFICULT AIRWAY / FACILITATED INTUBATION</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	Indications </b>\n\n
	    Indicated for adult and pediatric patients (8 years of age or older) where ventilatory
        support and facilitated intubation and are required, to include both medical and trauma
        conditions. For pediatric patients under the age of 8, a Physician\'s Orders is required
        to administer Etomidate. This procedure guideline should be used as a replacement for those
        situations where Midazolam (Versed) was indicated for airway management. These situations
        include, but are not limited to: \n\n
            \t •	Asthma With Dyspnea \n
            \t •	COPD \n
            \t •	Carbon Monoxide Inhalation \n
            \t •	Foreign Body Airway Obstruction \n
            \t •	Pulmonary Edema \n
            \t •	Burns \n
            \t •	Head Injuries \n\n
        <b>II.	 General Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	This is not a one-person procedure. Assistance should be utilized to facilitate the
            best possible patient care. For trauma patients, use a second crewmember to maintain in-line
            C-spine at all times \n\n
            \t •	Basic Life Support procedures should always occur concurrently with the initial assessment
            of any patient with the potential of hypoxia. These should include oxygen (NRB or BVM), manual
            jaw thrust, use of nasal and oral airways, adequate suctioning, etc. For those patients requiring
            BVM ventilation, an adequate seal, along with Sellick\'s Maneuver, is imperative to provide adequate
            ventilation and reduce the occurrence of gastric distention. \n\n
            \t •	Always pre-oxygenate for a minimum of 1 full minute with 100%% oxygen, being careful not to
            hyperventilate at an excessive rate or force. \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is NOT spontaneously breathing or is breathing ineffectively, provide
            ventilatory support using a BVM with 100%% oxygen at a rate of 10-12 breaths per minute. \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is spontaneously breathing and breathing effectively, provide blow-by 100%%
            oxygen via NRB without overriding patient\'s ventilations, thereby reducing the risk of gastric
            distention.\n\n
            \t •	Gather and test all necessary equipment prior to the initial attempt. Prepare the
            cardiac monitor for capnography by attaching the EtCO2 Filter Line (see <i>Capnography
            Procedure Guideline</i>). \n\n
            \t •	Intubation attempts should not be initiated without cardiac and SpO2 monitoring in place,
            unless circumstances exist that preclude monitoring (very rare). A second crewmember should
            read and announce out loud the patient\'s heart rate and SPO2 continuously during intubation
            attempts. \n\n
            \t •	Attempt to open the mouth by scissors (thumb and forefinger) technique. Proceed with intubation
            as outlined in the INTUBATION- OROTRACHEAL PROCEDURE GUIDELINE. \n\n
            \t •	If sedation is necessary to facilitate intubation (intact gag reflex, unable to open the
            mouth due to trauma, if the jaw is clenched, etc.) return to BLS procedures and: \n\n
                \t\t 1.	Ensure best oxygenation and ventilation. \n\n
                \t\t 2.	Ensure a patent IV line exists. \n\n
                \t\t 3.	If BP > or = 100 mmHg systolic, administer 4 mg Midazolam IV Push over 30-60 seconds
                for sedation. If BP &lt; 100 mmHg systolic, skip Midazolam and proceed to Etomidate. \n\n
                \t\t 4.	Wait 2 minutes and assess for adequate sedation for intubation. If patient adequately
                sedated, proceed with intubation as outlined in the Intubation – Endotracheal Procedure Guideline. \n\n
                \t\t 5.	If patient requires additional sedation to facilitate intubation, administer 0.3 mg/kg Etomidate
                x 1 dose IVP over 30-60 seconds for sedation (Maximum single dose of 40 mg).\n\n
                \t\t 6.	Wait 2 minutes and assess for adequate sedation for intubation. Attempt a maximum of 2
                attempts to pass endotracheal tube through the vocal cords. \n\n
                \t\t 7.	During intubation attempts, monitor for signs of hypoxia (significant decrease in HR,
                SpO2 levels below 90%%, signs of ventricular ectopy, etc.). If hypoxia develops, stop all
                procedures and immediately ventilate the patient with 100%% oxygen. \n\n
                \t\t 8.	Following intubation, confirm proper tube placement by auscultating the gastric area
                and the lungs bilaterally. Attach the EtCO2 Filter Line hub to the endotracheal tube hub.
                Ventilate the patient with a BVM and watch for appropriate capnographic waveforms with each BVM
                ventilation. Record a monitor strip as capnographic verification of appropriate endotracheal tube
                placement. \n\n
                \t\t 9.	If intubation successful, progress to Section III: Successful Airway Procedure. \n\n
                \t\t 10.	If unable to intubate after Etomidate, progress to Section IV: Failed Airway Procedure. \n\n
        <b>III.	Successful Airway Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	Continuously monitor airway status to maintain intubation, adequate ventilation and adequate
            perfusion. Continue to monitor the capnographic waveforms throughout ventilations to confirm
            appropriate tube placement. Following any movement of the intubated patient to include at transfer
            of care, record a capnographic waveform strip to determine that there has not been ET tube
            dislodgment.\n\n
            \t •	If necessary to maintain sedation post-intubation and BP > or = 100 mmHg systolic, administer
            Midazolam in 2-mg increments IVP every 3-5 minutes (maximum total dosage is 10 mg). Diazepam may
            be substituted for Midazolam in 5 mg increments Slow IVP every 3-5 minutes (maximum total dosage
            is 20 mg).\n\n
            \t <b>•	If the need arises for additional post intubation sedation administer Fentanyl 0.5 mcg/kg
            as a loading dose followed by a Fentanyl drip at 2 mcg/min may be used for post intubation
            sedation refractory to Midazolam.</b>\n\n
        <b>IV.	Failed Airway Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	Revert to Basic Life Support airway procedures as described in Section II: General
            Procedure, ensuring adequate ventilation and oxygenation with 100%% oxygen. \n
            \t •	Keep the airway clear of secretions, blood and vomitus. \n
            \t •	If able to effectively ventilate the patient with a BVM, consider insertion of a
            King Airway and continue ventilations (refer to the <i>King Airway Insertion Procedure Guideline</i>). \n\n
            If attempts at ventilation fail, or ventilations fail to perfuse the patient with oxygen,
            immediately perform a Cricothyrotomy (refer to the <i>Cricothyrotomy- Surgical Procedure Guideline</i>). \n
    </string>

    <!-- param_Foreign Body Airway Obstruction -->
    <string name="title_activity_fbao">FBAO</string>
    <string name="parameter_FBAO">
        <b><u>FOREIGN BODY AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>PARTIAL AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</b> \n\n
                \t\t•	Encourage the patient to continue spontaneous coughing and breathing efforts.
                    Do not interfere with the patient\'s own attempts to expel the foreign body,
                    but stay with the patient and monitor his or her condition. \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>Oxygen:</b> 15 LPM via NRB. \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
                \t\t•	Have equipment ready if patient condition deteriorates to COMPLETE AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION. \n\n
            \t <b>COMPLETE AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</b> \n\n
                \t\t<b>•	CONSCIOUS</b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	Adult / child: Abdominal thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t ii.	Pregnant / obese: Chest thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t iii.	Infant: Back blows and chest thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t iv.	Repeat until foreign object is expelled and airway is cleared OR patient
                        becomes unconscious. \n\n
                \t\t<b>•	UNCONSCIOUS</b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	<b>BVMR:</b> Open airway and attempt to ventilate. \n\n
                    \t\t\t ii.	Attempt to clear airway: \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 1.	Adult/child: Abdominal thrusts. \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 2.	Pregnant/obese: Chest thrusts. \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 3.	Infant: Back blows and chest thrusts. \n\n
                    \t\t\t iii.	Alternate attempts to ventilate with airway clearing techniques.
                        Once airway is cleared, support ventilations as needed with 100%% oxygen \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t•	If unable to clear airway with Basic Care and patient is unconscious: \n
            \t•	<b>Laryngoscope:</b> Visualize oropharynx and utilize Magill Forceps or suction as needed. \n
            \t•	<b>BVMR:</b> Open airway and attempt to ventilate. \n
            \t•	<b>Intubation:</b> If unable to ventilate and foreign object not visible with Laryngoscope. If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety, etc.) refer to Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline \n
            \t•	<b>Cricothyrotomy:</b> If unable to ventilate effectively after above attempts. \n\n
        <b>III.	Initial Medical Care:</b> establish after airway is secured. \n\n
        <b>NOTE: All patients should be encouraged to seek medical attention even
            if airway is cleared on scene.</b> \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Pulomary Edema-->
    <string name="title_activity_pe">Pulmonary Edema</string>
    <string name="parameter_pe">
        <b><u>PULMONARY EDEMA</u></b> \n\n
            \t If Pulse &lt; 60 and systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, refer to Bradycardia &amp; A.V.
                Blocks Clinical Care Guideline. \n
            \t If systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, refer to Shock (Non-Fluid Loss) Clinical Care Guideline. \n
            \t If systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, use treatment algorithm listed below: \n\n\n
        <b>BASIC CARE</b>
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity! Place patient in high-fowler\ʼs position
                or in patient\'s position of comfort. \n\n
            \t <b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations &lt; 10 or > 30 times a minute will
                be ventilated with Oxygen @ 15 LPM NRB until advanced care is established. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses).
                Indications: utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for dyspnea and HR &lt; 120. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL, repeat every 5 minutes if BP > 100 mmHg. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Do not administer NTG if the patient has taken phosphodiesterase (PDE) inhibitors
                    including: Viagra (sildenafil), Levitra (vardenafil) or Cialis (tadalafil) within
                    past 24 hours. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin Paste:</b> 1 inch applied transdermal. \n\n
            \t <b>•	CPAP:</b> (refer to CPAP Procedure Guideline for indications). Use the 10 cm H2O
                setting. For patients with a history of COPD or Asthma, use 8cm H2O PEEP setting for CPAP. \n\n
            \t •	If patient has chest pain, Fentanyl 1 mcg/kg, repeat every 5 minutes \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fentanyl</b> 1 mcg/kg IVP. If pain persists, after five minutes repeat dose once
                (maximum total dose 2 mcg/kg). \n\n
                \t\t *   *Do not administer in pregnant or possible pregnant patients. \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	<b>Physician\'s Orders</b> required for additional Morphine Sulfate.\n\n
            \t <b>•	Physician\ʼs Orders:</b> If the patient presents with fluid overload (rales, pitting edema > 2+),
                \t\t i.	<b>Bumetanide</b> 1 mg IVP for patients &lt; 70 kg or 2 mg IVP
            for patients > 70 kg.
            \t <b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety,
                etc.) refer to <u>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline</u>.




    </string>
</resources>
