<resources>
    <string name="title_activity_initial_medical_care">InitialMedicalCareActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pain_management">PainManagementActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="app_name">Sumter EMS Protocols</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <!-- Generic terms -->
    <string name="care_basic"><b>Basic Care</b></string>
    <string name="care_advanced"><b>Advanced Care</b></string>


    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>

    <!-- param_Asthma -->
    <string name="title_activity_asthma"><b><u>ASTHMA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_asthma">
        <u>DO NOT DELAY TRANSPORT WAITING FOR TREATMENT RESPONSE</u> \n\n
            \t •  <b>Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity! Place patient in high-fowler\'s
                position or patients position of comfort. \n\n
            \t •  <b>BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30 times a
                minute will be ventilated with OCYGEN @ 15 LPM until advanced care is established. \n\n
            \t •  <b>Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses
                ). <u>Indications:</u> utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for complaint of dyspnea, and
                HR &lt;120. \n\n
            \t •  <b>Capnography: </b>Apply nasal cannual filter line \n\n
            \t •  <b>Albuterol: </b>2.5 mg via updraft, may repeat one additional time, if effective (1)
                . For Pediatric patients, administer <b>Albuterol </b>2.5 mg with 2 ml NS via blow-by technique \n\n
            \t •	<b>If the patient has already administered a home treatment of Albuterol 30 minutes or less
                prior to EMS arrival,   Go directly to Combined Updraft as listed below.</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg and <b>Atrovent</b> 0.5 mg <b>combined</b> via updraft. \n\n
                 \t\t i.	Do not administer Albuterol/Atrovent if heart rate > 150 or significant
                ventricular ectopy. If during use of either medication ventricular ectopy develops,
                is unresolved or becomes worse, discontinue the updraft immediately. \n\n
                 \t\t ii.	Consider in-line <b>Albuterol/Atrovent</b> with CPAP if patient\'s condition warrants. \n\n
            \t •  <b>Epinephrine:</b> 0.01 mg/kg of either 1:1000 SQ (adequate perfusion), or 1:10,000 IV (inadequate
                perfusion) (maximum total dose 0.3 mg). <b><i>Physician\'s Orders required for additional
                Epinephrine.</i></b> \n\n
                 \t\ti.	<b>Epinephrine</b>  should be administered as first medication while updraft
                    medications are being prepared if patient presents as unstable upon initial contact. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Solu-Medrol:</b> 2 mg/kg IVP (maximum total dose 125 mg). \n\n
            \t •	<b>Magnesium Sulfate:</b> 2 Grams in 100 ml IV over 10 minutes on a 10gtt set. \n\n
            \t •	<b>CPAP:</b> (refer to <i>CPAP Procedure Guideline</i> for indications). 7.5 - 8.5 cm/H2O
                PEEP setting. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety, etc.)
                refer to <i>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i> \n\n
    </string>

    <!-- param_Carbon Monoxide -->
    <string name="title_activity_carbon_monoxide">Carbon Monoxide</string>
    <string name="parameter_carbonmono">
    <b>Carbon Monoxide</b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b>
            \t •	Remove patient from source to a safe environment. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial medical care:</b> Permit no activity. Place patient in high-fowler\'s
                position or in patient\'s position of comfort. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Oxygen</b> 15 LPM via NRB with tight fitting mask \n\n
                \t\t <b>i</b> Document exact time oxygen therapy was initiated and relay to receiving
                    facility. Be aware, pulse oximetry may indicate a false positive. \n\n
            \t <b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30
                times a minute will be ventilated with <b>Oxygen</b> @ 15 LPM until advanced care is established. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b>
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>RAD-57 Monitor: Initial <u>Reading</u></b> \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.</b> 0 to 12: treat underlying symptoms \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.</b> 13 to 25: transport to local hospital \n\n
                \t\t <b>iii.</b> 26 and greater: transport to hyperbaric c \n\nhamber
            \t <b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate
                (severe anxiety, etc.) refer to <i>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Early coordination with receiving facility with Hyperbaric Chamber is
                essential</b> \n\n
            \t •	Transportation arrangements will be made in conjunction with Dispatch. The following
                destinations have access to <i>Hyperbaric Chambers: </i> \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.</b> Florida Hospital Orlando, Orlando \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.</b> Shands (UF Health) Hospital, Gainesville \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_copd">COPD</string>
    <string name="parameter_copd">
        <b><u>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I. BASIC CARE</b>  \n\n
            \t <b>• Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity. Place patient in high-fowler\'s position
                or in patient\'s position of comfort. \n\n
            \t <b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations less than 10 or greater than 30 times
                a minute will be ventilated with <b>Oxygen</b> @ 15 LPM until advanced care is
                established. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses).
                <u>Indications:</u> utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for complaint of dyspnea, and HR
                &lt;120. \n\n
        <b>ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line, preferably before medications are
                administered if circumstances permit. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Albuterol:</b> 2.5 mg via updraft, repeat one time if effective. \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.</b>	Do not administer Albuterol/Atrovent if heart rate > 150 or significant
                    ventricular ectopy. If ventricular ectopy develops, is unresolved or becomes worse,
                    discontinue the updraft immediately. \n\n
            \t <b>•	If the patient has already administered a home treatment of Albuterol 30 minutes or less
                prior to EMS arrival, go directly to Combined Updraft as listed below. </b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg and <b>Atrovent</b> 0.5 mg <b>combined</b> via updraft. Consider
                in-line Albuterol/Atrovent with CPAP if patient\'s condition warrants. \n\n
            \t <b>•	CPAP:</b> Use 8 cm H2O PEEP setting. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Solu-Medrol:</b> 2 mg/kg IVP (maximum total dose 125 mg). \n\n
            \t <b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety,
                etc.) <i>refer to Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline.</i> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Difficult Airway / Facilitated Intubation-->
    <string name="title_activity_difficult_airway">DIFFICULT AIRWAY</string>
    <string name="parameter_diffairway">
        <b><u>DIFFICULT AIRWAY / FACILITATED INTUBATION</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	Indications </b>\n\n
	    Indicated for adult and pediatric patients (8 years of age or older) where ventilatory
        support and facilitated intubation and are required, to include both medical and trauma
        conditions. For pediatric patients under the age of 8, a Physician\'s Orders is required
        to administer Etomidate. This procedure guideline should be used as a replacement for those
        situations where Midazolam (Versed) was indicated for airway management. These situations
        include, but are not limited to: \n\n
            \t •	Asthma With Dyspnea \n
            \t •	COPD \n
            \t •	Carbon Monoxide Inhalation \n
            \t •	Foreign Body Airway Obstruction \n
            \t •	Pulmonary Edema \n
            \t •	Burns \n
            \t •	Head Injuries \n\n
        <b>II.	 General Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	This is not a one-person procedure. Assistance should be utilized to facilitate the
            best possible patient care. For trauma patients, use a second crewmember to maintain in-line
            C-spine at all times \n\n
            \t •	Basic Life Support procedures should always occur concurrently with the initial assessment
            of any patient with the potential of hypoxia. These should include oxygen (NRB or BVM), manual
            jaw thrust, use of nasal and oral airways, adequate suctioning, etc. For those patients requiring
            BVM ventilation, an adequate seal, along with Sellick\'s Maneuver, is imperative to provide adequate
            ventilation and reduce the occurrence of gastric distention. \n\n
            \t •	Always pre-oxygenate for a minimum of 1 full minute with 100%% oxygen, being careful not to
            hyperventilate at an excessive rate or force. \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is NOT spontaneously breathing or is breathing ineffectively, provide
            ventilatory support using a BVM with 100%% oxygen at a rate of 10-12 breaths per minute. \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is spontaneously breathing and breathing effectively, provide blow-by 100%%
            oxygen via NRB without overriding patient\'s ventilations, thereby reducing the risk of gastric
            distention.\n\n
            \t •	Gather and test all necessary equipment prior to the initial attempt. Prepare the
            cardiac monitor for capnography by attaching the EtCO2 Filter Line (see <i>Capnography
            Procedure Guideline</i>). \n\n
            \t •	Intubation attempts should not be initiated without cardiac and SpO2 monitoring in place,
            unless circumstances exist that preclude monitoring (very rare). A second crewmember should
            read and announce out loud the patient\'s heart rate and SPO2 continuously during intubation
            attempts. \n\n
            \t •	Attempt to open the mouth by scissors (thumb and forefinger) technique. Proceed with intubation
            as outlined in the INTUBATION- OROTRACHEAL PROCEDURE GUIDELINE. \n\n
            \t •	If sedation is necessary to facilitate intubation (intact gag reflex, unable to open the
            mouth due to trauma, if the jaw is clenched, etc.) return to BLS procedures and: \n\n
                \t\t 1.	Ensure best oxygenation and ventilation. \n\n
                \t\t 2.	Ensure a patent IV line exists. \n\n
                \t\t 3.	If BP > or = 100 mmHg systolic, administer 4 mg Midazolam IV Push over 30-60 seconds
                for sedation. If BP &lt; 100 mmHg systolic, skip Midazolam and proceed to Etomidate. \n\n
                \t\t 4.	Wait 2 minutes and assess for adequate sedation for intubation. If patient adequately
                sedated, proceed with intubation as outlined in the Intubation – Endotracheal Procedure Guideline. \n\n
                \t\t 5.	If patient requires additional sedation to facilitate intubation, administer 0.3 mg/kg Etomidate
                x 1 dose IVP over 30-60 seconds for sedation (Maximum single dose of 40 mg).\n\n
                \t\t 6.	Wait 2 minutes and assess for adequate sedation for intubation. Attempt a maximum of 2
                attempts to pass endotracheal tube through the vocal cords. \n\n
                \t\t 7.	During intubation attempts, monitor for signs of hypoxia (significant decrease in HR,
                SpO2 levels below 90%%, signs of ventricular ectopy, etc.). If hypoxia develops, stop all
                procedures and immediately ventilate the patient with 100%% oxygen. \n\n
                \t\t 8.	Following intubation, confirm proper tube placement by auscultating the gastric area
                and the lungs bilaterally. Attach the EtCO2 Filter Line hub to the endotracheal tube hub.
                Ventilate the patient with a BVM and watch for appropriate capnographic waveforms with each BVM
                ventilation. Record a monitor strip as capnographic verification of appropriate endotracheal tube
                placement. \n\n
                \t\t 9.	If intubation successful, progress to Section III: Successful Airway Procedure. \n\n
                \t\t 10.	If unable to intubate after Etomidate, progress to Section IV: Failed Airway Procedure. \n\n
        <b>III.	Successful Airway Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	Continuously monitor airway status to maintain intubation, adequate ventilation and adequate
            perfusion. Continue to monitor the capnographic waveforms throughout ventilations to confirm
            appropriate tube placement. Following any movement of the intubated patient to include at transfer
            of care, record a capnographic waveform strip to determine that there has not been ET tube
            dislodgment.\n\n
            \t •	If necessary to maintain sedation post-intubation and BP > or = 100 mmHg systolic, administer
            Midazolam in 2-mg increments IVP every 3-5 minutes (maximum total dosage is 10 mg). Diazepam may
            be substituted for Midazolam in 5 mg increments Slow IVP every 3-5 minutes (maximum total dosage
            is 20 mg).\n\n
            \t <b>•	If the need arises for additional post intubation sedation administer Fentanyl 0.5 mcg/kg
            as a loading dose followed by a Fentanyl drip at 2 mcg/min may be used for post intubation
            sedation refractory to Midazolam.</b>\n\n
        <b>IV.	Failed Airway Procedure</b> \n\n
            \t •	Revert to Basic Life Support airway procedures as described in Section II: General
            Procedure, ensuring adequate ventilation and oxygenation with 100%% oxygen. \n
            \t •	Keep the airway clear of secretions, blood and vomitus. \n
            \t •	If able to effectively ventilate the patient with a BVM, consider insertion of a
            King Airway and continue ventilations (refer to the <i>King Airway Insertion Procedure Guideline</i>). \n\n
            If attempts at ventilation fail, or ventilations fail to perfuse the patient with oxygen,
            immediately perform a Cricothyrotomy (refer to the <i>Cricothyrotomy- Surgical Procedure Guideline</i>). \n
    </string>

    <!-- param_Foreign Body Airway Obstruction -->
    <string name="title_activity_fbao">FBAO</string>
    <string name="parameter_fbao">
        <b><u>FOREIGN BODY AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>PARTIAL AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</b> \n\n
                \t\t•	Encourage the patient to continue spontaneous coughing and breathing efforts.
                    Do not interfere with the patient\'s own attempts to expel the foreign body,
                    but stay with the patient and monitor his or her condition. \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>Oxygen:</b> 15 LPM via NRB. \n\n
                \t\t•	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
                \t\t•	Have equipment ready if patient condition deteriorates to COMPLETE AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION. \n\n
            \t <b>COMPLETE AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</b> \n\n
                \t\t<b>•	CONSCIOUS</b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	Adult / child: Abdominal thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t ii.	Pregnant / obese: Chest thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t iii.	Infant: Back blows and chest thrusts \n\n
                    \t\t\t iv.	Repeat until foreign object is expelled and airway is cleared OR patient
                        becomes unconscious. \n\n
                \t\t<b>•	UNCONSCIOUS</b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	<b>BVMR:</b> Open airway and attempt to ventilate. \n\n
                    \t\t\t ii.	Attempt to clear airway: \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 1.	Adult/child: Abdominal thrusts. \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 2.	Pregnant/obese: Chest thrusts. \n\n
                        \t\t\t\t 3.	Infant: Back blows and chest thrusts. \n\n
                    \t\t\t iii.	Alternate attempts to ventilate with airway clearing techniques.
                        Once airway is cleared, support ventilations as needed with 100%% oxygen \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t•	If unable to clear airway with Basic Care and patient is unconscious: \n
            \t•	<b>Laryngoscope:</b> Visualize oropharynx and utilize Magill Forceps or suction as needed. \n
            \t•	<b>BVMR:</b> Open airway and attempt to ventilate. \n
            \t•	<b>Intubation:</b> If unable to ventilate and foreign object not visible with Laryngoscope. If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety, etc.) refer to Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline \n
            \t•	<b>Cricothyrotomy:</b> If unable to ventilate effectively after above attempts. \n\n
        <b>III.	Initial Medical Care:</b> establish after airway is secured. \n\n
        <b>NOTE: All patients should be encouraged to seek medical attention even
            if airway is cleared on scene.</b> \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Pulomary Edema-->
    <string name="title_activity_pulmonary_edema">Pulmonary Edema</string>
    <string name="parameter_pe">
        <b><u>PULMONARY EDEMA</u></b> \n\n
            \t If Pulse &lt; 60 and systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, refer to Bradycardia &amp; A.V.
                Blocks Clinical Care Guideline. \n
            \t If systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, refer to Shock (Non-Fluid Loss) Clinical Care Guideline. \n
            \t If systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg, use treatment algorithm listed below: \n\n\n
        <b>BASIC CARE</b>
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity! Place patient in high-fowler\ʼs position
                or in patient\'s position of comfort. \n\n
            \t <b>•	BVMR:</b> Patients with inadequate ventilations &lt; 10 or > 30 times a minute will
                be ventilated with Oxygen @ 15 LPM NRB until advanced care is established. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Prescription Inhaler:</b> metered dose every 10 minutes (maximum 3 total doses).
                Indications: utilize patient\'s prescribed inhaler for dyspnea and HR &lt; 120. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL, repeat every 5 minutes if BP > 100 mmHg. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Do not administer NTG if the patient has taken phosphodiesterase (PDE) inhibitors
                    including: Viagra (sildenafil), Levitra (vardenafil) or Cialis (tadalafil) within
                    past 24 hours. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin Paste:</b> 1 inch applied transdermal. \n\n
            \t <b>•	CPAP:</b> (refer to CPAP Procedure Guideline for indications). Use the 10 cm H2O
                setting. For patients with a history of COPD or Asthma, use 8cm H2O PEEP setting for CPAP. \n\n
            \t •	If patient has chest pain, Fentanyl 1 mcg/kg, repeat every 5 minutes \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fentanyl</b> 1 mcg/kg IVP. If pain persists, after five minutes repeat dose once
                (maximum total dose 2 mcg/kg). \n\n
                \t\t *   *Do not administer in pregnant or possible pregnant patients. \n\n
                    \t\t\t i.	<b>Physician\'s Orders</b> required for additional Morphine Sulfate.\n\n
            \t <b>•	Physician\ʼs Orders:</b> If the patient presents with fluid overload (rales, pitting edema > 2+),
                \t\t i.	<b>Bumetanide</b> 1 mg IVP for patients &lt; 70 kg or 2 mg IVP
            for patients > 70 kg.
            \t <b>•	Intubation:</b> If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate (severe anxiety,
                etc.) refer to <u>Difficult Airway-Facilitated Intubation Guideline</u>.
    </string>

    <!--param_Acute Coronary Syndrome-->
    <string name="title_activity_acs">Acute Coronary SyndromePulmonary Edema</string>
    <string name="parameter_acs_header"><b><u>ACUTE CORONARY SYDROME</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_acs">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Permit no activity. Place patient in their
                position of comfort. If BP &lt; 90 mmHg, encourage the patient to lie supine. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Prescription Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL every 5 minutes (maximum 3 total doses).
                Indications: utilize patient\'s prescribed NTG for cardiac-related chest discomfort and BP
                > 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative change
                in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Aspirin:</b> 324 mg PO (chew and swallow). \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL, repeat every 5 minutes if BP > 90 mmHg. \n\n
                \t\t i.	    Give strong consideration to IV insertion prior to administration of Nitroglycerin. \n
                \t\t ii.	Do not administer NTG if the patient has taken phosphodiesterase (PDE) inhibitors
                    including: Viagra (sildenafil), Levitra (vardenafil) or Cialis (tadalafil) within past 24
                    hours. \n
            \t <b>•	Nitroglycerin Paste:</b> 1 inch applied transdermal. \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.	Fentanyl</b> 1mcg/kg IVP repeat every 5 minutes (Fentanyl 1 mcg/kg IVP.
                    If pain persists, after five minutes repeat dose once \n
                \t\t (maximum total dose 2 mcg/kg).* \n\n
                \t\t *Do not administer in pregnant or possible pregnant patients. \n\n
                \t\t i.	<b>Physician\'s Orders</b> <i>required for additional Fentanyl.</i> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Ondansetron:</b> 4 mg slow IVP for nausea and vomiting. May give IM if no IV. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Second IV:</b> Establish a second IV of NS at KVO or Saline-lock. Indications: STEMI,
                shock, widespread ST depression, or any medication by drip. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Dysrhythmias:</b> If dysrhythmias are noted, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care
                Guideline</i> for specific treatments. \n\n
        III.	<b>Determine Transport Destination:</b> refer to <i>Transport – Cardiac Administrative
            Policy</i>. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Asystole/PEA-->
    <string name="title_activity_asystole">Asystole/PEA</string>
    <string name="parameter_asystole_header"><b><u>ASYSTOLE – PEA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_asystole">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	ABCD:</b> Perform appropriate action following American Heart Association (AHA)
                CPR Guidelines. \n\n
            \t •	Follow <i>End of Life Administrative Policy</i>, as necessary. \n\n
            \t •	If arrest > 4 minutes: perform 2-minutes of CPR prior to assessing rhythm. \n\n
            \t •	If arrest &lt; 4 minutes or witnessed arrest: assess rhythm. \n\n
            \t •	Reassess rhythm after every 2 minute period of CPR; assess radial pulse if organized rhythm,
                do not exceed 10 seconds. If no radial pulse or unsure, resume CPR \n\n
                \t\t i.	If using an AED, follow the manufacturer\'s prompts for cardiac arrest management.\n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Vascular Access:</b> IV or IO. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Epinephrine:</b> 1 mg 1:10,000 IVP/IO followed by 10ml NS bolus. Repeat every 3 - 5
                minutes of continued arrest \n\n
            \t <b>•	Advanced Airway</b> (endotracheal tube, King Tube). Search for and treat 6 H\'s &amp; 5 T\'s. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Reconfirm placement after repositioning or moving patient. Administer 8-10
                    breaths/minute via BVM; avoid hyperventilation.\n\n
            \t <b>•	Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP/IO or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes (maximum total
                dose 10 mg). Indications: combative post-resuscitation patients. Use with caution
                for systolic BP &lt; 100 mmHg.
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Pulomary Edema-->
    <string name="title_activity_bradycardia">Bradycardia</string>
    <string name="parameter_bradycardia_header"><b><u>BRADYCARDIA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_bradycardia">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. Place patient in
            Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative change
                in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached \n\n
            \t <b>•	Monitor and Observe</b> closely for changes in patients with adequate perfusion. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Non-Symptomatic</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	Apply Transcutaneous Pacer on standby. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Symptomatic</b> \n\n
                \t\t <b><u>i.	Sinus Bradycardia</u></b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>1.	Atropine Sulfate:</b> 0.5 mg IVP, repeat every 3 - 5 minutes (maximum
                    total dose 3 mg). \n\n
                \t\t <b><u>ii.	2nd or 3rd Degree Block</u></b> \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>1.	Sedation: Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes
                        (maximum total dose 10 mg). \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>2.	Transcutaneous Pacing:</b> 60 BPM and increase mA from minimum setting until
                        consistent electrical capture is achieved. Verify mechanical capture and increase mA
                        by 10 for safety margin. Refer to <i>Transcutaneous Pacing Procedure Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Dopamine:</b> 5 mcg/kg/min IV drip, reassess every 5 minutes for patient response and
                titrate in 5 mcg/kg/min increments (max total dose 20 mcg/kg/min). \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.	Indications:</b> unstable patient (inadequate perfusion) with verified pulse
                    rate &lt; 60 unresponsive to Atropine or TCP. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Narrow Complex Tachycardia - irregular-->
    <string name="title_activity_narrow_complex_irreg">Narrow Tach Irreg</string>
    <string name="parameter_narrowtach_irreg_header"><b><u>NARROW COMPLEX TACHYCARDIA – IRREGULAR</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_narrowtach_irreg">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. Place
                patient in Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative
                change in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Vagal Maneuvers:</b> perform Valsalva maneuver or apply cool moisture to face. \n\n
            \t •	If patient has a history of WPW, refer to <i>Wide Complex Tachycardia Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t <b><u>STABLE</u></b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS Lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Check blood glucose level:</b> if blood glucose is &lt; 60 or > 250, also refer to
                Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Administer a fluid bolus 250 ml of NS. Continue IV infusion KVO. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Diltiazem:</b>  15 mg slow IVP over 2 minutes \n\n
            \t •<b>Diltiazem:</b>	 25 mg slow IVP over 2 minutes, if rhythm unchanged. \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG</b> after conversion \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>.\n\n
            \t <b><u>UNSTABLE – Systolic BP &lt; 90 mm Hg, AMS, Cardiac-focused chest pain</u></b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached, if rapidly possible. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Consider sedation: Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes (max dose 10 mg) \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 100 joules \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Consider fluid bolus 250 ml of NS if no response to cardioversion. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 200 joules \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Diltiazem:</b> 15 mg IV over 2 minutes \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 300 joules \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 360 joules \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG</b> after conversion \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Narrow Complex Tachycardia - regular-->
    <string name="title_activity_narrow_complex_reg">Narrow Tach Regular</string>
    <string name="parameter_narrowtach_reg_header"><b><u>NARROW COMPLEX TACHYCARDIA – REGULAR</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_narrowtach_reg">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort.
                Place patient in Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mmHg. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative
                    change in condition and/or every 15 minutes. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Vagal Maneuvers:</b> perform Valsalva maneuver or apply cool moisture to face. \n\n
            \t <b><u>STABLE</u></b>
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Check blood glucose level:</b> if blood glucose is &lt; 60 or > 250, also refer
                to Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Administer a fluid bolus 250 ml of NS. Continue IV infusion KVO. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Adenosine:</b> 12 mg rapid IVP/IO. If no conversion, \n\n
            \t <b>•	Adenosine:</b> 12 mg rapid IVP/IO \n\n
            \t <u>Indication:</u> stable patients with regular narrow-complex tachycardia (PSVT, AT).
            \t •	If rhythm converts briefly to reveal an irregular rhythm, refer to <i>Narrow Complex
                Tachycardia – Irregular Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t •	Consider possible causes of dysrhythmia (6 H\'s and 6 T\'s). \n\n
            \t •	If patient condition deteriorates, refer to <b>UNSTABLE</b> treatment. \n\n
            \t •	<b><u>Physician Consult</u></b> for alternative treatments if above antiarrhythmic
                agents are unsuccessful in rhythm conversion or rate control. \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post
                Resuscitation Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t <b><u>UNSTABLE</u></b> – Systolic BP &lt; 90 mm Hg, AMS, cardiac-focused chest pain \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached, if rapidly possible. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Consider Sedation: Midazolam</b> 2 mg IVP or Intra-Nasal, repeat every 5 minutes
                (maximum total dose 10 mg). \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 100 joules.
            \t <b>•	Fluid Bolus:</b> Consider fluid bolus 250 ml of NS if no response to cardioversion
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 200 joules
            \t •	If no response administer 12mg of <b>Adenosine</b>
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 300 joules
            \t •	If no response, <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 360 joules
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>.
    </string>

    <!--param_Narrow Complex Tachycardia - irregular-->
    <string name="title_activity_rosc">Post Resuscitation/ROSC</string>
    <string name="parameter_rosc_header"><b><u>POST RESUSCITATION MANAGEMENT</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_rosc">
        <b><u>INDICATIONS</u></b> \n\n
            \t •	POST CARDIAC ARREST WITH RETURN OF CIRCULATION \n\n
            \t •	PRESENCE OF A PALPABLE BLOOD PRESSURE \n\n
            \t •	MENTAL STATUS MAY VARY \n\n
        <b><u>ADVANCED CARE</u></b> \n\n
            \t •	Continue treatment per appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline and presumed
                underlying cause</i>. \n\n
            \t •	Airway management to include oxygen and ventilation support. Do not
                over-ventilate. \n\n
            \t •	Maintain Pulse oximetry to 94% or greater \n\n
            \t •	Maintain Capnography between 35 and 45 mm Hg \n\n
            \t •	Monitor cardiac rhythm for changes and treat per appropriate Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	12 Lead EKG: Monitor for possible STEMI alert criteria. \n\n
            \t •	Treat hypotension (systolic BP &lt; 90 mm Hg) with IV fluids and Dopamine per appropriate
                Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	If patient remains unresponsive refer to Induced Hypothermia Procedure Guideline. \n\n


    </string>

    <!--VAD-->
    <string name="title_activity_vad">VAD</string>
    <string name="parameter_vad_header"><b><u>VENTRICULAR ASSISTANCE DEVICE</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_vad">
        This Appendix applies to the management of patients who have a ventricular assist device (VAD)
        also referred to a left ventricular assist device (LVAD) implanted. The VAD is a mechanical pump
        used to support the heart\’s pumping function and positive blood flow on individuals who have severe
        heart failure. \n\n
        <b>INITIAL MEDICAL CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Perform initial assessment: vital signs, oxygen saturation, pre-treatment 12-Lead ECG,
                focused history (SAMPLE, OPQRST), and physical exam. Inquire if the patient has an old ECG. \n\n
                \t\t o	Provide OXYGEN @ 100% via NRB mask or assist ventilations/oxygenation as indicated. \n\n
            \t •	Listen to heart sounds. The heart sounds may be faint. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Check for a functioning VAD:</b> These devices are usually implanted below the heart
                    in the abdominal cavity area. Use a stethoscope to listen for constant humming or whirling
                    sound. This sound confirms the VAD is functioning. \n\n
                \t\t o	The nature of the VAD function provides positive constant flow (it is a centrifugal
                    pump) therefore a <b>pulse may not be palpable</b> in these patients. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Blood Pressure:</b> A manual blood pressure may not be obtainable. An automated blood
                    pressure monitoring device may provide a reading with a narrow pulse pressure. \n\n
                \t\t o	Treatment of these patients must be based on the mean arterial pressure (MAP). The normal
                    MAP should be between 60 and 90 mm/Hg. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Pulse Oximetry:</b> These readings may not be accurate due to the continuous flow provided
                    by the VAD. \n\n
                \t\t o	Monitor side capnography for ventilation and oxygenation effectiveness. \n\n
        <b>UNRESPONSIVE PATIENT</b> \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is unresponsive to stimuli: \n\n
                \t\t o	Open the airway and ventilate/oxygenate as necessary. \n\n
                \t\t o	Obtain a blood glucose level and treat per Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia
                    Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	Listen for a functioning VAD by auscultating over the abdomen. \n\n
                \t\t o	If the VAD has a whirling sound it is properly functioning. \n\n
                \t\t o	<b>DO NOT PERFORM CPR!</b> \n\n
            \t 	A VAD or LVAD is surgically implanted to the left ventricle. External cardiac compressions
                may dislodge the VAD causing death. \n\n
            \t •	If the VAD is silent have the caregiver or family member check the device external pump
                controller and power supply. \n\n
                \t\t o	<b>LISTEN TO THE CAREGIVER!</b> These individuals are experts in these devices and
                    know/understand how to operate and troubleshoot the system. \n\n
                \t\t o	VAD patients are instructed to always have a backup bag with 2 charged batteries
                    and a second pump controller. \n\n
                \t\t o	Contact the VAD coordinator listed on the patient’s information card. \n\n
            \t•	If the VAD is inoperative despite troubleshooting and battery replacement, then CPR
                is indicated as per cardiac arrest parameter. \n\n

        <b>RESPONSIVE PATIENT:</b> \n\n
            \t •	Perform a subjective interview to determine chief complaint and history of present illness. \n\n
            \t •	Monitor ECG and obtain a 12 lead ECG if chest pain, ischemic symptoms, shortness of breath or
                weakness is reported. \n\n
                \t\t o	Any cardiac dysrhythmias must be treated per the appropriate practice parameter. \n\n
                \t\t o	If electrical therapy is indicated on a conscious patient, the patient may be sedated
                    (time permitting) as per parameter. \n\n
            \t•	Establish IV access and provide fluid resuscitation as indicated based on patient\’s condition
                and hydration status. \n\n
            \t•	Assess for any other concurrent medical conditions or symptoms and treat per the appropriate
                parameter. \n\n

        <b>TRANSPORT OF PATIENT:</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	ALL VAD patients with cardiac, respiratory, neurological or infectious disease complaints
                must be transported to the VAD center.</b> \n\n
                \t\t o	Florida Hospital Orlando and UF Health Shands are the only local approved VAD centers. \n\n
                \t\t o	Contact the VAD coordinator as soon as possible and notify them of the transport. \n\n
            \t •	VAD patients presenting with minor complaints may be transported to any receiving facility
                as long as they have their backup batteries and equipment with the patient. \n\n
                \t\t o	These complaints include, but are not limited to: \n\n
            \t 	Minor sprains, strains or orthopedic injuries \n\n
            \t 	Hypoglycemia without severe signs or symptoms \n\n
            \t 	Isolated extremity lacerations \n\n
            \t •	Don’t forget the family member/caregiver! \n\n
                \t\t o	The family member/caregiver must <b>ACCOMPANY</b> the patient in the ambulance. \n\n
                \t\t o	These individuals have intimate knowledge of the patient\’s condition, the system and
                    usually have legal authority to sign on behalf of the patient. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Bring all VAD equipment, backup bags, charger and batteries with the patient!</b> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Ventricular Fibrillation & Pulseless VTACNarrow Complex Tachycardia - irregular-->
    <string name="title_activity_vfib">VFib/Puleless VTAC</string>
    <string name="parameter_vfib_header"><b><u>VENTRICULAR FIBRILLATION &amp; PULSELESS V-TACH</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_vfib">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Check for responsiveness - Shake and shout, Pain stimulation \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Initiate CCR</b> (Cardio-Cerebral Resuscitation) – Continuous chest
                compressions \n\n
                \t\t i.	At least 100 compressions per minute with at least a 2 inch compression depth \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Continue CCR for two minutes \n\n
            \t •	Place “Quick Combo Pads” (Defibrillation Pads) \n\n
            \t <b>•	Defibrillate</b> initially at 200 joules or follow directions from AED \n\n
                \t\t <b>i.	Second Defibrillation setting should be at 300 joules</b> \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.	All subsequent defibrillations should be at 360 joules</b> \n\n
            \t •	Immediately following the shock, return to 2-minutes of CCR.  It is imperative that
                there be no break in the compressions other than the second or two that it takes to
                change out rescuers performing CCR. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE:</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Venous Access:</b>  If possible, while CCR is being performed, establish a large-bore
                IV/IO of NS \n\n
            \t <b>•	Epinephrine:</b>  1 mg of 1:10,000 IVP/IO.  Repeat every 3-5 minutes of continued arrest.
                Medication should be administered while CCR is in progress. Follow with 10ml NS bolus \n\n
            \t <b>•	Antiarrhythmic Agents:</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	Amiodarone:  300 mg IVP/IO followed by 10ml NS bolus. Repeat 150 mg once, if
                    necessary. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Magnesium Sulfate:  2 Gram mixed in 10 ml NS slow IVP/IO over 5 minutes.
                    Repeat x 1 dose (max total dose of 2 Grams). Indications:  Torsade’s de Pointes or
                    the maximum dose of 450 mg of amiodarone has been administered and the patient still
                    presents in ventricular fibrillation or pulseless ventricular tachycardia. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Airway:</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	OPA:  Place an OPA \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Place the patient on oxygen with a non-rebreather mask set at 10-12 L/min. \n\n
                \t\t Precaution:  Be prepared to remove the OPA and NRBM if the patient vomits.  Have the
                    suction unit prepared and ready. \n\n
                \t\t iii.	Endotracheal Intubation / King Tube Insertion:  If there is a ROSC or if time
                    permits and there is no interruption of CCR, the NRBM may be replaced by an ET or King
                    and high-liter flow O2.  If a BVM is used, the patient should be bagged using a rate of
                    6-8 one-handed ventilations per minute only. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Analysis:</b>  Following the post-shock 2 minutes of CCR, either allow the AED to
                    analyze the rhythm or if using a manual defibrillator, briefly analyze the rhythm. \n\n
                \t\t i.	If the rhythm continues as Ventricular Fibrillation or Pulseless Ventricular
                    Tachycardia, \n\n
                    \t\t\t <b>1.	Defibrillate</b> again at 360-joules.  Continue the “Shock – Post-Shock”
                    cycle as long as he patient remains in VF or pulseless VT. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	If the patient has a return of spontaneous circulation (palpable pulses,
                    respirations, blood pressure), \n\n
                    \t\t\t 1.	Place the ET or King as previously discussed if the patient will tolerate
                        same or utilize a non-rebreather mask at 10-12 L/min and then initiate… \n\n
            \t <b>•	Post Conversion Drip Therapy:</b>
                \t\t <b>i.	Amiodarone:</b>  150 mg IV/IO bolus followed by an Amiodarone 150 mg IV/IO drip
                    (over 10 minutes). \n\n
                    \t\t\t 1.	150 mg in 100 ml D5W: 150 mg/10 min = 15.0 mg/min (100gtts/min on 10gtt IV
                        set or 600ml/h on IV pump). \n\n
                    \t\t\t 2.	If rhythm converts prior to administration of an antiarrhythmic agent, administer
                        the bolus and the drip as above. \n\n
                    \t\t\t 3.	If any Amiodarone has been administered via bolus during the resuscitative
                        efforts, administer only the Amiodarone drip as above. \n\n
                \t\t <b>ii.	Magnesium Sulfate:</b>  2G IV/IO drip (over 1 hour) \n\n
                    \t\t\t 1.	2G in 250 ml D5W: 2 G/hr. =33.4mg/min (250gtts/min on 60gtt IV set or 250ml/hr.
                        on IV pump) \n\n
                    \t\t\t 2.	Indications: Torsade’s de pointes \n\n
                \t\t <b>iii.	Midazolam:</b>  2 mg IV/IO or Intra-Nasal.  Repeat every 3-5 minutes (max total
                    dose of 10 mg). Indications:  Combative, post-resuscitation patients. Use with caution in
                    presence of hypotension (BP &lt; 90 mmHg \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Wide Complex Tachycardia - Irregular-->
    <string name="title_activity_wide_complex">Wide Complex Tach</string>
    <string name="parameter_wide_complex_header"><b><u>WIDE COMPLEX TACHYCARDIA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_wide_complex">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Initial Medical Care:</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. Place patient
                in Trendelenburg position if BP &lt; 90 mm/Hg systolic. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG:</b> Perform as early as possible, repeat with any significant negative change
                in condition and/or every 15 minutes.\n\n
            \t <b>•	Capnography:</b> Apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS Lock attached \n\n
            \t <b>STABLE</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Monitor and Observe</b> closely for changes in patients with adequate perfusion. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Amiodarone</b> 150 mg IV drip (over 10 minutes). Indications: stable patients with
                regular wide-complex tachycardia \n\n
            \t <b>•	Magnesium Sulfate</b> 2G in 10 ml NS Slow IV (over 5 minutes), repeat x 1 dose
                (max total dose 2G). Indications: torsade\’s de pointes.  \n\n
            \t <b>•	Physician\ʼs Consult:</b> for alternative treatments if above antiarrhythmic agents are
                unsuccessful in rhythm conversion or rate control.  \n\n
            \t <b>UNSTABLE</b>  \n\n
            \t <b>•	Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 100 J. <u>Indications:</u> unstable patients with inadequate
                perfusion. Consider pre-medication with <b>Midazolam:</b> 2 mg IV or Intra-Nasal, repeat
                every 3-5 minutes until adequate relaxation sedation is achieved prior to procedure (
                max total dosage is 10 mg). Use <b>Midazolam</b> with caution in the presence of hypotension
                (BP &lt; 100 mmHg). \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 200 J \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Amiodarone</b> 150mg IV Bolus \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 300 J \n\n
            \t •	If no change: <b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 360 J \n\n
            \t •	Post-Conversion Maintenance Therapy: \n\n
                \t\t i.	<b>Amiodarone</b> 150 mg IV drip (over 10 minutes) \n\n
                    \t\t\t <u>Indications:</u> If rhythm converts prior to antiarrhythmic agent \n\n
                \t\t ii.	<b>Magnesium Sulfate</b> IV drip of 2 Gram/hr. \n\n
                    \t\t\t <u>Indications:</u> If <b>Magnesium</b> converts torsade\’s de pointes \n\n
            \t •	If rhythm converts, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline or Post Resuscitation
                Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
        <b><u>III.	NOTES:</u></b> \n\n
            \t <b>1.	Amiodarone drip:</b> (150 mg in 100 ml NS) \n\n
                \t\t 150 mg/10 min = 15.0 mg/min (100gtts/min on 10gtt IV set or 600 ml/h on IV pump) \n\n
            \t <b>2.	Magnesium Sulfate drip:</b> (2G in 250 ml D5W) \n\n
                \t\t 2G/hr = 33.4 mg/min (250gtts/min on 60gtt IV set or 250 ml/hr on IV pump \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Abdominal Pain-->
    <string name="title_activity_abdominal_pain">Abdominal Pain</string>
    <string name="parameter_abd_pain_header"><u><b>ABDOMINAL PAIN</b></u></string>
    <string name="parameter_abd_pain">
        <b>CONSIDER CARDIAC ETIOLOGY</b> \n\n
        Refer to acute coronary syndrome Clinical care Guideline \n\n
        <b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	If hypotension/shock is present, refer to Shock Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Check blood glucose level:</b> if blood glucose is &lt; 60 or > 250, also refer
                to <i>Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Administer nothing by mouth.</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Assess distal/femoral pulses.</b> \n\n
            \t <b>•	Ondansetron:</b> 4 mg slow IVP for nausea and vomiting \n\n
            \t <b>*Do not administer in patients that are pregnant or who may be pregnant.</b> \n\n
            \t <i><b>•	Physician’s Orders</b> for pain management. Refer to Pain Management Clinical
                Care Guideline</i> \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!-- param_allergic_reaction_&_anaphalctic_shock -->
    <string name="title_activity_allergic_reaction">Allergic Reaction</string>
    <string name="parameter_allergic_reaction_header"><b><u>ALLERGIC REACTION &amp; ANAPHYLACTIC SHOCK</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_allergic_reaction">
        <b>STABLE</b> \n\n
        <b>I.	Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	If wheezing is present and heart rate &lt; 160, Albuterol 2.5 mg via updraft.
                (Repeat as necessary.) \n\n
            \t •	If hives (urticaria) or history of systemic reaction in past: <b>Diphenhydramine</b>
                    1 mg/kg IVP not to exceed 50 mg slowly over 2-3 minutes. If no IV, may give IM. \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Solu-Medrol:</b> 125 mg IVP (adults) or 2 mg/kg IVP (Pediatrics).
        <b>UNSTABLE</b>
        <b>I.	Initial Medical Care</b>
            \t •	ADULTS: Administer <b>Epinephrine</b> 1:10,000: 0.3mg IVP. If no IV, administer <b>Epinephrine</b>
                1:1000: 0.3mg SQ. \n\n
            \t •	PEDIATRICS: Administer <b>Epinephrine</b> 1:10,000 0.01mg/kg IVP or IO. If no IV or IO,
                administer <b>Epinephrine </b>1:1000 0.01 mg/kg SQ. \n\n
            \t •	NEWBORN: Administer <b>Epinephrine</b> per Length-Based Tape. \n\n
        II.	If Systolic BP &lt; 90 refer to <i>Shock Clinical Care Guideline.</i> \n\n
        III.	If wheezing present and heart rate &lt; 160, <b>Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg via updraft. \n\n
        IV.	If no response to above treatment, administer <b>Solu-Medrol </b>125 mg IVP (adults) or 2
                mg/kg IVP (pediatrics) \n\n
        V.	If hives (urticaria) or history of systemic reaction in past, \n\n
            \t •	<b>Diphenhydramine</b> 1 mg/kg IVP not to exceed 50 mg slowly over 2-3 minutes. If no IV,
                may give IM.
        VI.	<i><b>Physician Orders:</b> May repeat Epinephrine at dosages listed above.</i>

        <b><i>DIPHENHYDRAMINE IS CONTRAINDICATED IN ASTHMA PATIENTS</i></b>
    </string>

    <!-- param_altered_mental_status-->
    <string name="title_activity_ams">AMS</string>
    <string name="parameter_altered_mental_header"><b><u>ALTERED MENTAL STATUS</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_altered_mental">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
        II.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        III.	If hypotensive with signs of decreased tissue perfusion, refer to Shock Clinical Care
                Guideline. Consider patient may still be experiencing hypoglycemia, hyperglycemia or substance
                abuse. \n\n
        IV.	<b>If blood glucose level &lt; 60:</b> Refer to <i>Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical
                Care Guideline.</i> \n\n
        V.	If substance abuse suspected: Naloxone 1 mg slow IVP or Intra-Nasal every 3 minutes as needed if
            transient response observed (maximum total dosage 8 mg).\n\n
            \t •	Use good judgment with Naloxone. Only administer if there is probable cause for an opiate
                overdose.
            \t •	Refer to Length Based Tape for pediatric administration of Naloxone. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!-- param_cerebrovascular_accident -->
    <string name="title_activity_cva">CVA</string>
    <string name="parameter_cva_header"><b><u>CEREBROVASCULAR ACCIDENT</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_cva">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care:</b> Maintain head and neck in neutral alignment; elevate head
                of stretcher 15-30 degrees if BP > 100 mm Hg. Protect paralyzed limbs from injury. \n\n
            \t •	Confirm accurate time when patient last seen normal. \n\n
            \t •	Oxygen: Nasal Cannula at 2 LPM; if patient is hypoxic, apply appropriate oxygen adjunct
                with appropriate liter flow.\n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Check blood glucose level:</b> If &lt; 60, refer to <i>Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia
                Clinical Care Guideline.</i>  \n\n
            \t <b>•	12 Lead EKG</b>
            \t •	<b>Cincinnati Stroke Scale</b> (F.A.S.T.): Complete on scene. If 1 abnormal assessment from
                FAST, complete the  <u>Stroke Alert sheet</u>, STROKE ALERT and Destination Criterion will determine
                the appropriate destination for patients based on exclusion/inclusion criteria. Do not delay
                transport. Document initial assessment and subsequent changes. Deliver completed form to
                ED staff \n\n
            \t <b>•	Determine Transport Destination:</b> refer to <i>Transport – Stroke Administrative Policy</i>. \n\n
            \t <b>•	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Ondansetron:</b> 4 mg slow IVP for nausea and vomiting. If no IV, may give IM. \n\n
                \t\t <b>*Do not administer if pregnant or possibility of pregnancy.</b> \n\n
            \t •	For patients presenting with severe hypertension, refer to <i>Hypertensive Crisis
                Clinical Care Guideline.</i> \n\n
            \t <b>•	MEND Exam:</b> Perform during transport. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Second IV:</b> Establish a second peripheral IV (Saline-lock).
                \t\t <u>Indications:</u> Stroke Alert and time permitting. \n\n
            \t <b>•	Documentation:</b> Document witness information (name and telephone numbers),
                symptom onset (time last seen normal), Mend Exam, and location of any missed IVs. \n\n\n

    </string>

    <!-- param_drug_overdose_and_poisoning -->
    <string name="title_activity_drug_overdose">OD/Poison</string>
    <string name="parameter_drug_overdose_header">
        <b><u>DRUG OVERDOSE &amp; POISONING</u></b> \n
        <u>A <b>TOXIC EXPOSURE</b> shall be defined as:</u> 
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_drug_overdose_subheader">The intentional or unintentional ingestion, inhalation,
        injection, dermal or ocular application of a medication, chemical, biological or active substance
        that results in immediate or potentially delayed effects.</string>
    <string name="parameter_drug_overdose">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
        II.	<b>Check blood glucose level:</b> refer to <i>Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care
            Guideline</i>, as indicated. \n\n
        III.	If altered sensorium, refer to <i>Altered Mental Status Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
        IV.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        V.	<b>Contact the American Association of Poison Control Centers</b>, through the Communications
            Center or by calling 1-800-222-1222, to obtain information regarding the initial stabilization
                and management of the exposure. \n\n
            \t <b>The American Association of Poison Control Centers</b> will provide medical direction,
                home management, and follow-up per their standard operating protocols as required by
                Florida Statutes. Communications can cancel the call via the Poison Control’s authority. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_Environmental_Cold_Emergencies-->
    <string name="title_activity_environmental_cold">Environmental Cold</string>
    <string name="parameter_environmental_cold_header"><b><u>ENVIRONMENTAL COLD EMERGENCIES</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_environmental_cold">
        <b><u>All patients should have body temperature assessed</u></b> \n\n
        <b><u>I.	FROSTBITE</u></b> \n\n
            \t • <b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Remove wet garments and move patient to a warm environment ASAP. \n\n
            \t •	Elevate affected body part and cover with loosely applied, dry, sterile dressings. \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Physician\'s Orders:</b> Morphine Sulfate as per Medical Control. \n\n
        <b><u>II.	MILD / MODERATE SYSTEMIC HYPOTHERMIA</u></b> \n\n \n\n
        Body temperature of 90-95 degrees F. Patient may be conscious or have an altered sensorium with shivering. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Warm <b>Oxygen:</b> 15 LPM via NRB. \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	IV fluids; warm is preferred. \n\n
            \t •	Remove wet clothing and protect patient against heat loss and wind chill. \n\n
            \t •	Place patient in horizontal position avoiding rough movement and excess activity. \n\n
            \t •	Completely dry patient and cover patient with insulated blanket. \n\n
        <b><u>III.	SEVERE SYSTEMIC HYPOTHERMIA</u></b> \n\n
        A body temperature of 90 degrees F or less. Patient may appear uncoordinated with poor muscle control
        or stiff, simulating rigor mortis. There will be NO shivering. Patient may be confused, withdrawn,
        disoriented, and comatose. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	DO NOT INTUBATE UNLESS PATIENT IS APNEIC. \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	Warm IV tubing and Oxygen tubing with hot packs. \n\n
            \t •	Refer to appropriate Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	Refer to MILD/MODERATE SYSTEMIC HYPOTHERMIA above. \n\n
            \t •	Administer no more than 3 defibrillations until re-warmed \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_environmental_heat">Environmental Heat</string>
    <string name="parameter_environmental_heat_header">
        <b><u>ENVIRONMENTAL HEAT EMERGENCIES</u></b> \n\n
        <b><u> All patients should have body temperature assessed Avoid rebound hypothermia with rapid cooling
            – Shivering is too far!</u></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_environmental_heat">
        <b>I.	HEAT CRAMPS</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV of NS or LR \n\n
            \t •	Move patient to a cool environment and transport \n\n
            \t •	<b>Physician\'s Orders:</b> For severe cramps - <b>Magnesium Sulfate</b> drip 5 Grams in 250
                ml of D5W over 30 minutes. \n\n
        <b>II.	HEAT EXHAUSTION</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Move patient to a cool environment as soon as possible after initial medical assessment. \n\n
            \t •	Place patient in a supine position with feet elevated \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV of NS or LR \n\n
            \t •	<b>Fluid Boluses:</b> in increments of 500 ml. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Evaluate/auscultate lungs throughout administration of fluid. If rales present, withhold
                    (maximum total dosage of 1 Liter). \n\n
            \t •	<b>Physician\’s Consult: </b>Contact Medical Control for further administration of fluid boluses \n\n
            \t •	Initiate rapid cooling \n\n
                \t\t i.	Remove as much clothing as possible to facilitate cooling. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Sponge the patient with tepid water or cover with wet sheet. Blow ambient air across
                    the patient to maximize evaporation. \n\n
                \t\t iii.	Apply icepacks to axilla, back of neck and groin area \n\n
        <b>III.	HEAT STROKE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV of NS or LR \n\n
            \t •	Move patient to a cool environment as soon as possible after initial medical assessment. \n\n
            \t •	Place patient in semi-reclining position with head elevated 15-30 degrees if systolic BP is
                greater than 100mmHg. Evaluate and take precautions for increased intracranial pressure. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Fluid Boluses:</b> in increments of 500 ml. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Evaluate/auscultate lungs throughout administration of fluid. If rales present, withhold
                    (maximum total dosage of 1 Liter). \n\n
            \t •	<b>Physician\’s Consult:</b> Contact Medical Control for further administration of fluid
                boluses \n\n
            \t •	Initiate rapid cooling \n\n
                \t\t i.	Remove as much clothing as possible to facilitate cooling. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	Sponge the patient with tepid water or cover with wet sheet. Blow ambient air
                    across the patient to maximize evaporation. \n\n
                \t\t iii.	Apply icepacks to axilla, back of neck and groin area. \n\n\n

    </string>

    <!--param_esophageal_foreign_body_obstruction-->
    <string name="title_activity_esophageal_foreign_body_obstruction">Esophageal Obstruction</string>
    <string name="parameter_esophageal_obstruct_header"><b><U>ESOPHAGEAL FOREIGN BODY OBSTRUCTION</U></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_esophageal_obstruct">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	If airway obstruction present, refer to <i>Foreign Body Airway Obstruction Clinical Care
                Guideline.</i>   \n\n
        II.	 <b>Airway Maneuvers</b> \n\n
            \t •	Protect against aspiration. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Oxygen:</b> nasal cannula at 2 LPM; if patient hypoxic apply appropriate oxygen adjunct
                with appropriate liter flow. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Cardiac Monitor</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Capnography:</b> apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
        III.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        IV.	Place patient in position of comfort. \n\n
        V.	Encourage coughing. \n\n
        VI.	<b>Glucagon:</b> 1 mg IVP. May repeat once after 5 minutes (maximum total dose 2 mg). \n\n
            \t •	Consider if patient is going to be transported \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_excited_delirium-->
    <string name="title_activity_excited_delirium">Excited Delirium</string>
    <string name="parameter_excited_delirium_header"><b><u>EXCITED DELIRIUM</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_excited_delirium">
        <b><u>Initial considerations</u></b> \n\n
            \t •	Law Enforcement will play an important role in the actions to control these patients. \n\n
            \t •	These patients are truly out of control and have a potentially life threatening medical
                emergency. \n\n
            \t •	Patient will possibly present with Paranoia, disorientation, hyper-aggression, hallucinations,
                tachycardia, increased strength and hyperthermia. \n\n
            \t •	Emphasis shall be placed on scene safety, appropriate use of both chemical and physical
                restraints and the aggressive treatment of the patient’s agitation and underlying cause of
                this condition. \n\n
        \t <b>I.	Basic Care</b> \n\n
            \t\t •	Ensure scene safety and enough personnel are on scene to safely manage the patient. \n\n
            \t\t •	Ensure all Taser activity (if deployed) is canceled prior to contact. \n\n
            \t\t •	Manually restrain patient as needed to provide safe contact for care and maintain until
                sedated. \n\n
        \t <b>II.	Advance Care</b> \n\n
            \t\t •	Initial Sedation (based on safest way to make contact) \n\n
            \t\t •	Ketamine \n\n
            \t\t •	1.0 mg/kg Nasal atomizer (max 100 mg) 50mg/Nares \n\n
            \t\t •	 2 Mg/ Kg IV (Max dose of 400 Mg) \n\n
            \t\t •	4.0 mg/kg IM (Max 500 mg) \n\n
        \t <b>III.	Post Administration Care</b> \n\n
            \t\t • Place patient on stretcher in a supine position. \n\n
            \t\t • Apply 4 point soft restraints. \n\n
            \t\t • Maintain a controlled airway. \n\n
            \t\t • IV /10 accesses as per protocol. \n\n
            \t\t • Vital signs q 5 minutes. \n\n
            \t\t • Check Blood Glucose level \n\n
            \t\t • SA02, ETC02, and EKG Monitoring. \n\n
        \t <b>IV.	Maintenance Medication Dose</b> \n\n
            \t\t •	 Ketamine \n\n
            \t\t •	1.0 mg/kg Nasal atomizer (Max 100 mg) or \n\n
            \t\t •	Ketamine \n\n
            \t\t •	 2mg/kg IV/I0 (Max 200mg) \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_extra_pyramidal_activity-->
    <string name="title_activity_extra_pyramidal">Extra Pyramidal</string>
    <string name="parameter_extra_pyramidal_header"><b><u>EXTRA PYRAMIDAL SYNDROME</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_extra_pyramidal">
        <b>I.	Extra Pyramidal Syndrome Types</b> \n\n
            •	Buccal Lingual Crisis – Thick Tongue \n\n
            •	Oculogyric Crisis – Eyes roll to one side, confusion \n\n
            •	Rectus Abdominus – Muscle Spasms \n\n
            •	Torticollis – Neck frozen in one position \n\n
            •	Opisthotonus – Back Muscle Spams \n\n
        <b>II.	Initial Medical Care.</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. \n\n
        <b>III.	IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        <b>IV.	Diphenhydramine:</b> \n\n
            •	Adults: 25 mg IVP, may give IM if no IV. \n\n
            •	Pediatrics: 1 mg/kg IVP, may give IM if no IV \n\n
        <b>V.	Physician’s Orders:</b> If signs/symptoms reoccur, contact Medical Control to repeat 
                    Diphenhydramine administration. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_hazardous_material-->
    <string name="title_activity_hazardous_material">HazardousMaterialActivity</string>
    <string name="parameter_hazardous_material_header"><b><u>HAZARDOUS MATERIALS</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_hazardous_material">
        A <b>TOXIC EXPOSURE</b> is defined as: \n\n
        The intentional or unintentional ingestion, inhalation, injection, dermal or ocular application of a
        medication, chemical, biological active substance, resulting in immediate or potentially delayed
        effects \n\n
            \t I.	PROTECT YOURSELF, OTHER EMERGENCY PERSONNEL AND CIVILIANS. Do not attempt to treat
                or remove the patient from exposure without appropriate PPE. \n\n
            \t II.	Request response of Fire Department Haz-Mat Team \n\n
            \t III.	Maintain safe zone and assess scene from appropriate distance per Emergency Response
                Guide Book.\n\n
            \t IV.	Coordinate efforts with Fire Department Haz-Mat Team Incident Commander. \n\n
            \t V.	The patient should be decontaminated by Haz-Mat Team and clearance should be obtained
                prior to transferring care to EMS under the following conditions: \n\n
                \t\t •	Appropriate protective clothing and respiratory protection should be worn by transport
                    crew members.\n\n
                \t\t •	Determination of the appropriate level of BSI should be done in conjunction with the
                    Haz¬Mat Team Incident Commander or Safety Officer. \n\n
                \t\t •	The patient should be wrapped in a blanket and outer plastic sheet to prevent
                    contamination. An alternative would be to place the patient in a special transport
                    unit that is equipped with contamination safety measures. \n\n
                \t\t •	If possible, a reserve transport unit should be used so that in the event of serious
                    contamination, it can remain out of service for decontamination. \n\n
                \t\t •	Maintain maximum patient compartment ventilation; <b>fresh air is important.</b> \n\n
            \t VI.	<b>Initial Medical or Trauma Care.</b> \n\n
            \t VII.	Follow the appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline</i> for specific cases. \n\n
            \t VIII.	Consult with the initial receiving facility\'s physician early in the incident. The hospital
                should be alerted about the impending arrival of the patient and the circumstances surrounding the
                event, including the type of hazardous material involved. \n\n
                \t\t •	<b>Do not enter the hospital with the patient without the ED physician\'s approval</b> \n\n
            \t IX.	<b>Personal Decontamination per your organization\’s Exposure Control Plan.</b> \n\n
            \t X.	<b>Contact the American Association of Poison Control Centers</b>, through the Communications
                Center or by calling <b>1-800-222-1222</b>, to obtain information regarding the initial
                stabilization and management of the exposure. \n\n
            \t XI.	<b>The American Association of Poison Control Centers</b> will provide medical direction,
                provide home management, and follow-up per their standard operating protocols as required by
                Florida Statutes 401.23(13) and 395.1027. Consult with the Haz-Mat Team reference contacting the
                appropriate agencies such as Chemtrec (1-800-535- 5053) or Infotrac (1-800-535-5053) for specific
                hazardous material information. \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_hypertensive_crisis-->
    <string name="title_activity_hypertensive_crisis">Hypertensive Crisis</string>
    <string name="parameter_hypertensive_crisis_header">
        <b><u>HYPERTENSIVE CRISIS</u></b> \n\n
        <b>TREATABLE HYPERTENSION is defined as: \n
        Systolic BP > 220 mmHg OR Diastolic BP > 120 mmHg</b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_hypertensive_crisis">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care:</b> Maintain head and neck in neutral alignment; elevate head
                of stretcher 45-90 degrees. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Oxygen:</b> Nasal Cannula at 2 LPM. If patient is hypoxic, apply appropriate oxygen adjunct
                with appropriate liter flow. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>12 Lead EKG</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Blood Pressure:</b> verify with manual cuff. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Stroke Exam:</b> <i>Refer to Cerebrovascular Accident Guideline if positive</i>. \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Nitroglycerin:</b> 0.4 mg SL. If effective, repeat every 3-5 minutes. \n\n
            \t •	If NTG is ineffective after 2 doses and heart rate is greater than 60 BPM; \n\n
            \t •	<b>Labetalol:</b> 10 mg slow IVP over 1 minute. May repeat every 5 minutes until systolic
                blood pressure is 180 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure is 90 mm Hg (maximum total dosage
                30 mg). \n\n
            \t •	<b>Ondansetron:</b> 4 mg slow IVP for nausea or vomiting; may be given IM if no IV. May repeat
                once. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Do not administer if patient is pregnant or possibility of pregnancy.</b>\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_hypoglycemia & hyperglycemia-->
    <string name="title_activity_hypo_hyper_glycemia">Hypo/Hyper Glycemia</string>
    <string name="parameter_hypo_hyper_glycemia_header">
        <b><u>HYPOGLYCEMIA &amp; HYPERGLYCEMIA</u></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_hypo_hyper_glycemia">
            <b>•	Obtain history of time of patient\'s last medication dosage and patient\'s last meal.</b> \n
            <b>•	Obtain and record blood sugar level.</b> \n\n
        <b>I.	HYPOGLYCEMIA</b> \n\n
        BLOOD GLUCOSE LEVEL &lt; 60 AND/OR WITH ASSOCIATED SIGNS AND SYMPTOMS \n\n
            •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            •	<b>Instant Glucose:</b> 30 Grams orally if the patient is conscious and able to swallow
                effectively. \n\n
            •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            •	<b>Adult administration:</b>  250 ml bag of D10W administered via a 10 qtt set.  Administer at
                an open rate. Evaluate responsiveness throughout administration. \n\n
            •	<b>Blood glucose level should be evaluated after 50% (125 ml’s) have been administered.  If
                the BGL is 120 or higher, stop administration and evaluate the patient.</b> \n\n
            •	250 ml of D10W is equal to 25Gms of Dextrose 50%. \n\n
            •	<b>Pediatric Administration:</b>  Administer D10W at a dose of 1ml per KG.  Evaluate patient
                and blood glucose level.  May administer second dose if needed. \n\n
            •	If IV cannot be established, administer <b>Glucagon</b> 1 mg IM. *Patient must be transported \n\n
            •	In cases where the patient is combative and out of control placing the responders in an
                unsafe environment, Dextrose 50% (25 Gms) may be administered to the patient.  A fluid bolus
                of 100 ml of normal saline shall follow this treatment. \n\n
        <b>II.	HYPERGLYCEMIA</b> \n\n
        BLOOD GLUCOSE LEVEL > 250 AND/OR WITH ASSOCIATED SIGNS AND SYMPTOMS \n\n
            •	<b>Initial Medical Care  IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            •	<b>Fluid Bolus:</b> Administer a fluid bolus of 500 ml of Normal Saline. Continue IV infusion
                KVO. \n\n
            •	<b>Physician\'s Consult:</b> If prolonged transport time, contact Medical Control regarding
                further fluid boluses. \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_hypo_hyper_glycemia_sub">
        There may be times when patients are refusing further treatment or transport after a
        hypoglycemic episode. These patients will be allowed to refuse transport under the <i>Refusal of
        Service Administrative Policy</i>.
    </string>

    <!--param_nausea_vomiting-->
    <string name="title_activity_nausea_vomiting">Nausea/Vomiting</string>
    <string name="parameter_nausea_vomiting_header"><b><u>NAUSEA &amp; VOMITING</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_nausea_vomiting">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical Care.</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. \n\n
        II.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        III.	<b>Ondansetron:</b> 4 mg slow IVP; may be given IM if no IV. May repeat once as needed \n\n
            <b>•	Do not administer in patient who are pregnant or who may be pregnant.</b> \n\n
        IV.	Look for underlying causes and treat per appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_non_environmental_hyperthermia-->
    <string name="title_activity_non_environmental_hyperthermia">Hyperthermia Nonenv</string>
    <string name="parameter_non_enviro_hyperthermia_header">
        <b><u>NON-ENVIRONMENTAL HYPERTHERMIA</u></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_non_enviro_hyperthermia_subheader">
        \t\t\t A Temperature of 105 degrees F or higher \n
        \t\t\t Hyperthermia caused by, but not limited to: \n
        \t\t\t •	Infectious diseases (most common), \n
        \t\t\t •	Post-Surgical or Post-Procedural Hospital \n
        \t\t\t Acquired Infection \n
        \t\t\t •	Amphetamines, \n
        \t\t\t •	malignant hyperthermia, \n
        \t\t\t •	Cocaine, PCP and other similar drugs.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_non_enviro_hyperthermia">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical \trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Common Infectious diseases include but are not limited to: Influenza, Measles, MRSA,
                Tuberculosis, Meningitis, Streptococcal Pneumonia, Pertussis (whooping cough), and Hemorrhagic
                Fevers. \n\n
                \t\t 	Refer to the <i>Infectious Disease Exposure Hemorrhagic Fever and PPE Procedure
                    Guideline</i> if you suspect your patient\’s Fever is caused by an infectious hemorrhagic
                    disease. \n\n
            \t •	Attention should be given to personal protection from exposure of the patient\’s bodily fluids
                and the aerosolized contents of their exhalation. \n\n
                \t\t 	Refer to the <i>Infectious Disease Exposure and PPE Procedure Guideline</i> \n\n
            \t •	The patient should be transported in a well ventilated ambulance, limiting the amount of time
                the patient and responders spend in a closed unventilated space.\n\n
        II.	Establish an IV of NS (preferably antecubital fossae) and administer at 120 ml / hr. \n\n
            •	Limit IV attempts, Invasive airway, and any other procedures that precipitate the release of
                bodily fluids if you suspect the patient’s condition is caused by a hemorrhagic infectious
                disease. \n\n
        III.	Begin cooling of patient.\n\n
            •	Remove as much clothing as possible to facilitate cooling.\n\n
            •	Sponge the patient with tepid water or cover with wet sheet. Blow ambient air across the
                patient to maximize evaporation.\n\n
            •	Apply icepacks to axilla, back of neck and groin area.\n\n
        IV.	Consider that patients who have elevated temperature caused by <b>any</b> infection are also at
            risk for Sepsis and Septic Shock. Refer to the <i>Sepsis / Sepsis Alert Clinical Care Guideline</i> to
            determine if in addition to the precipitating cause of the fever, they also fit these criteria and
            treat as appropriate. \n\n
        V.	<b><i>Physician\'s Consult: for further management of patient\'s condition.</i></b>
        VI.	Epidemic and Pandemic information is typically identified and forwarded by the Centers for Disease
            Control and The Florida Department of Health. In times of outbreak this guideline should serve as a
            starting point in recognition, and be followed by specific recommendations approved and distributed
            by these organizations.\n\n
        VII.	If Altered Mental Status or other symptoms exist, refer to the appropriate <i>Clinical Care
                Guideline.</i> \n\n
        VIII.	Expedite transport. \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_psychological_&_behavioral_emergencies-->
    <string name="title_activity_psychological_behavioral">Psych/Behavioral</string>
    <string name="parameter_psychological_behavior_header">
        <b><u>PSYCHOLOGICAL &amp; BEHAVIORAL EMERGENCIES</u></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_psychological_behavior_sub_header">
        <b>CONSIDER MEDICAL ETIOLOGY OF PSYCHOLOGICAL &amp; BEHAVIORAL DISORDER Refer to appropriate <i>Clinical
            Care Guideline</i>:</b> \n
            \t\t 	Hypoxia: <b><i>Medical Care</i></b> \n
            \t\t 	Substance Abuse: <b><i>Drug Overdose &amp; Poisoning</i></b> \n
            \t\t 	Neurologic Disease: <b><i>Cerebrovascular Accident</i></b> \n
            \t\t 	Metabolic Derangements: <b><i>Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia</i></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_psychological_behavior">
        \t I.	Establish <b>Scene and Personal Safety</b> - Call law enforcement to scene. Above all,
            <b>do nothing to jeopardize your own safety.</b> \n\n
        \t II.	Determine and document if patient is a threat to self or others, or if patient is unable to
            care or provide for self. Protect patient from harm to self or others. \n\n
        \t III.	Attempt to calm the patient. \n\n
        \t IV.	Physically restrain as necessary, if danger unavoidable. Document use, type, time applied, and
            reasons for application. Document distal circulation, sensory, and motor assessments every 5
            minutes. \n\n
        \t V.	<b>Initial Medical Care.</b> \n\n
        \t VI.	<b>Physician Consult:</b> in ALL instances where refusal of transport is being considered.
        \t VII.	If patient becomes severely agitated, to the point of interfering with patient care and / or
            becomes a physical danger to the crew\'s well-being: \n\n
            \t\t 	<b>Physician\'s Orders: Midazolam</b> 4 mg Slow IVP, IM, or Intranasal. \n\n
            \t\t 	Consulting Physician will determine repeat doses as needed. \n\n
        \t VIII.	If needed, consult law enforcement for assistance with transport of the unwilling patient. \n
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_psychological_behavior_end">
        <b>MIDAZOLAM is not to be administered to patients with CNS depression, patients taking narcotics, or
            patients taking Lithium Carbonate.</b> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_scene_rehab-->
    <string name="title_activity_scene_rehab">Scene Rehab</string>
    <string name="parameter_scene_rehab_header"><b><u>SCENE REHABILITATION</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_scene_rehab">
        The Scene Rehabilitation Area will be staffed by at least one Paramedic. There shall also be a
        dedicated ALS Transport. In the event that a civilian patient requires the use of this ambulance,
        another shall be dispatched to take its place. The Paramedic in charge of the Rehab Area will become
        the Rehabilitation Unit Leader or “Rehab”. \n\n
        Initial care received in the Rehab Area will consist of: \n
            \t •	Removal of All PPE  \n
            \t •	Vital Signs Measurements \n
            \t •	Passive &amp; Active Cooling as needed. Refer to <i>Environmental Heat Emergency Care
                Guideline</i> \n
            \t •	REST \n
            \t •	Nourishment \n
            \t •	Minimum of 24oz of water \n\n
        If vital signs are within the acceptable range listed below the responder will remain in rehab for: \n
        10-min if: \n
            \t •	Depletion of a total of one 30-minute SCBA cylinder \n
            \t •	After 20 minutes of intense work without SCBA \n\n
        20-min if: \n
            \t •	Depletion of two or more 30-minute SCBA cylinders \n
            \t •	Depletion of one 45- or 60-minute SCBA cylinder \n
            \t •	Whenever encapsulating chemical protective clothing is worn \n
            \t •	After 40 minutes of intense work without SCBA \n\n
        If vital signs are outside of the acceptable range, the responder should be moved into an ambulance
        or designated treatment area and cared for by a paramedic until they return to normal \n\n
            \t Vital Sign Acceptable Range \n
            \t •	Heart rate: &lt; 85\u0025 age specific maximum \n
            \t •	Temperature: &lt; 102\º F tympanic \n
            \t •	Systolic Blood Pressure: &lt; 160 mmHg \n
            \t •	Diastolic Blood Pressure &lt; 110 mmHg \n
            \t •	Respirations: > 10 or &lt; 30 \n
            \t •	Pulse oximetry: &gt; 94\u0025 \n
            \t •	ETCO (Carbon Monoxide) &lt; 10\u0025 \n
            \t •	Fatigue abates and skin condition within normal limits \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_scene_rehab_chart">
        <b><u>Vital Signs Acceptable Range</u></b> \n\n
        Age Predicted 85\u0025 Max Heart Rate \n
        Age	85 Percent \n
        20-25	170 \n
        26-30	165 \n
        31-35	160 \n
        36-40	155 \n
        41-45	152 \n
        46-50	148 \n
        51-55	140 \n
        56-60	136 \n
        61-65	132 \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_scene_rehab_end">
        <b><u>Transport Considerations</u></b> \n\n
            \t •	All unstable personnel will be immediately referred to Rehab for treatment and transport. \n\n
            \t •	All personnel who require further treatment beyond cooling and rehydration, or those who are
                unable to return to normal vital signs within 30-minutes will be treated per appropriate care
                guideline and transported for continual care. \n\n
            \t •	Personnel who receive IV fluid therapy, regardless of vital signs, on scene will be transported
                per appropriate transport guideline.  \n\n
            \t •	The Incident Commander or Ranking Officer on the scene should be notified in any case that
                results in the transport of a responder.\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_seizure-->
    <string name="title_activity_seizure">Seizure</string>
    <string name="parameter_seizure_header"><b><u>SEIZURE</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_seizure">
        <b>I.	Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Vomiting / aspiration precautions. Place nothing in mouth during seizure.\n
            \t •	If blood glucose level &lt; 60, refer to Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care Guideline.\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached.\n\n
        II.	<b>Midazolam</b> 5 mg IVP, IM or Intra-nasal (Max does of 10 mg.)\n\n
        III.	For Pediatric Patients:  0.1 mg/kg (Max dose of 5.0 mg.).\n\n
        IV.	Observe patient\'s sensorium and airway during postictal period. If hypoxic seizures, drug-induced
            seizures, seizures from head trauma, stroke or eclampsia are suspected, treat as above and refer
            to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline</i> for further treatment.\n\n
        V.	If febrile seizure, move to cool environment and cool patient.\n\n
        VI.	<b>Physician\'s Orders:</b> If seizure activity continues, contact Medical Control.\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_sepsis & sepsis alert-->
    <string name="title_activity_sepsis">Sepsis</string>
    <string name="parameter_sepsis_header"><b><u>SEPSIS &amp; SEPSIS ALERT</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_sepsis">
        Sepsis is a rapidly progressing, life-threatening condition due to systemic infection.
        Sepsis must be recognized early and treated aggressively to prevent progression to shock and death.
        Sepsis can be identified when the following markers of the <b>Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome
        (SIRS)</b> are present in a patient with suspected infection: \n\n
            \t\t •   Temperature > 38o C (100.4o F) or &lt; 36o C (96.8o F) \n
            \t\t •	Respiratory Rate > 20 breaths /min \n
            \t\t •	Heart rate > 90 beats/min \n\n
        In addition to physiologic markers of SIRS, severe sepsis may cause hypoxia and inadequate organ
        perfusion, resulting in metabolic acidosis marked by elevated blood lactate levels and decreased ETCO2
        levels (measured by capnography). \n\n

        <b>SEPSIS ALERT:</b> \n\n
        The purpose of a <b>Sepsis Alert</b> is to provide pre-arrival Emergency Department notification in order
        to facilitate rapid assessment and treatment of a suspected severe sepsis patient.  A <b>Sepsis Alert</b>
        will be instituted for patients meeting the following three (3) criteria: \n\n
            \t I.	Suspected infection \n\n
            \t II.	Two or more of the following: \n
                \t\t •	Temperature &gt; 38º C (100.4º F) or &lt; 36º C (96.8º F) \n
                \t\t •	Respiratory Rate &gt; 20 breaths /min \n
                \t\t •	Heart rate &gt; 90 beats/min \n\n
            \t III.	ETCO2  ≤ 25mmHg <b>OR</b> Lactate &gt; 4mMol/L

        <b><u>I.	Basic Life Support</u></b> \n
            \t •	Supplemental 100\u0025 Oxygen \n\n

        <b><u>II.	Advanced Life Support</u></b> \n
            \t •	Full ALS assessment and treatment \n
            \t •	Notify hospital of incoming <b>Sepsis Alert</b> prior to arrival \n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n
                \t\t o	Administer NS 250 ml boluses until systolic BP &gt; 90 mmHg \n
                \t\t o	Total amount of IVF should not exceed 2000 ml \n
                \t\t o	Boluses may be given in rapid succession if systolic BP remains below 90 mmHg \n\n

        <b>III.	Contact Medical Control for Additional Orders if Needed</b> \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_shock-->
    <string name="title_activity_shock">Shock</string>
    <string name="parameter_shock_header"><b><u>SHOCK</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_shock">
        <b>I.	HEMORRHAGIC</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care.</b> Control and stop external hemorrhage.\n
            \t •	Place patient in Trendelenburg position. \n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish 2 large bore IV lines \n
            \t •	<b>Fluid bolus</b> in 500 ml increments, re-evaluate every 500 ml. Titrate systolic BP &gt;
                90 mmHg. (Maximum infusion of 3 liters)\n
            \t •	<b>Physician\'s Orders:</b> For further fluid administration orders. \n\n
        <b>II.	RELATIVE HYPOVOLEMIA</b> \n\n
            \t Neurologic, metabolic, psychogenic, or other volume depleted states. \n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care.</b> \n
            \t •	Place patient in Trendelenburg position \n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish IV of NS. \n
            \t •	<b>Fluid bolus</b> in 500 ml increments, re-evaluate every 250 ml. Titrate systolic BP
                &gt; 100 mmHg. Once systolic BP &gt; 100 mm Hg, continue infusion at 120 ml/hr. (Max
                infusion of 1 liter) \n
            \t •	<b>Physician\'s Orders:</b> For further fluid administration orders. \n\n
        <b>III.	CARDIOGENIC</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n
            \t •	Place patient in Trendelenburg position. \n
            \t •	Consider heart rate etiology and treat per appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline. </i> \n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV of NS. \n
            \t •	<b>Fluid bolus</b> of 250 ml \n
            \t •	If no response or condition worsens, start a <b>Dopamine</b> Drip at 5 mcg / kg / min.
                Increase the drip in 5 mcg / kg / min increments every 5 minutes. Titrate to systolic BP
                &gt; 100 mm Hg. (Maximum of 20 mcg / kg / min). \n\n
        <b>IV.	PEDIATRIC</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV of NS. \n
            \t •	<b>Fluid bolus</b> in 20 ml / kg increments. Refer to Length Based Tape for administration
                of fluids and / or medications. Maximum of 3 boluses \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_sickle_cell_anemia-->
    <string name="title_activity_sickle_cell_anemia">Sickle Cell</string>
    <string name="parameter_sickle_cell_header">
        <b><u>SICKLE CELL ANEMIA CRISIS</u></b> \n\n
        <B>POSSIBLE SIGNS AND SYMPTOMS:</B>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_sickle_cell">
                \t\t\t•	Severe dyspnea. \n
                \t\t\t•	Severe pain secondary to hypoxia or vaso-occlusive disease process. \n
                \t\t\t•	Pain may include any large muscle mass. \n\n

        I.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
        II.	Keep patient as quiet as possible to minimize OXYGEN needs.  \n\n
        III.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        IV.	<b>Fluid bolus</b> of 250 ml. Continue IV infusion at 120 ml / hr. \n\n
        V.	<b>Fentanyl </b>1 mcg/kg; after five minutes may repeat once (maximum total dosage 2 mcg/kg). \n\n
            \t\t *Do not administer in pregnant or possible pregnant patients. \n\n
        VI.	<b>Physician\'s Orders:</b> additional administration of Fentanyl. \n\n
        VII.	Refer to <i>Acute Coronary Syndrome Clinical Care Guideline</i> for symptoms,
            chief complaint, or multi-lead diagnostic EKG evaluation that suggests Angina / Myocardial
            Infarction \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_syncope, near syncope, general_weakness-->
    <string name="title_activity_syncope">Syncope/GenWeakness</string>
    <string name="parameter_syncope_header"><b><u>SYNCOPE, NEAR SYNCOPE &amp; GENERAL WEAKNESS</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_syncope">
        I.	Look for causes for syncope, near syncope and general weakness. These episodes may be indicative of
            a severe problem. Correct underlying abnormalities and refer to the appropriate <i>Clinical Care
            Guideline.</i> \n\n
        II.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	C-spine precautions as indicated. \n\n
        III.	<b>12 Lead EKG:</b> Document 12 Lead or Multi-Lead monitor assessment, if available, for all
            possible cardiac-related syncope. \n\n
        IV.	Obtain blood glucose level. Refer to <i>Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia Clinical Care Guideline</i> if
            Blood Glucose &lt; 60 or &gt; 250. \n\n
        V.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        VI.	If hypotension present, <b>fluid bolus</b> of 250 ml to maintain a systolic BP &gt; 90 mm Hg \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_childbirth_emergency-->
    <string name="title_activity_childbirth">Childbirth</string>
    <string name="parameter_childbirth_header"><b><u>CHILDBIRTH (EMERGENCY)</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_childbirth">
        <b>PHASE I: LABOR</b> \n\n
            \t A.	Obtain history and determine if there is adequate time to transport. \n\n
            \t B.	Inspect for bulging perineum, crowning or whether patient is involuntarily pushing
                with contractions. If contractions are two minutes apart or less, or any of the above
                are present, prepare for delivery. <b>Do not attempt to restrain or delay delivery unless
                prolapsed cord.</b> \n\n
            \t C.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t D.	If mother is hyperventilating, encourage eye contact and coach her to take slow,
                deep breaths. \n\n
            \t E.	If mother becomes hypotensive or lightheaded at any time, administer <b>fluid boluses</b> in
                increments of 250 ml, to titrate systolic BP &gt; 90 mm Hg and apply Oxygen 15 LPM via NRB mask
                or assist with BVM. \n\n
            \t F.	Position mother supine on flat surface, if possible. If time permits, put on full
                blood and body secretion barriers. \n\n
            \t G.	Open OB pack. Place drapes over mother\'s abdomen and beneath perineum. Prepare bulb
                syringe, cord clamps and blankets to receive infant. \n\n
        <b>II. PHASE II: DELIVERY</b> \n\n
            \t A.	Allow head to deliver passively. Control rate of delivery by placing palm of one hand
                gently over occiput. Protect perineum with pressure from other hand. \n\n
            \t B.	Gently suction infant\'s nose and mouth as soon as the head delivers if time allows.
                Once head is delivered, allow it to passively turn to 1 side to allow shoulders to deliver.\n\n
            \t C.	Feel around the infant\'s neck for the umbilical cord (nuchal cord). If present, attempt to
                gently lift it over the baby\'s head. If unsuccessful, double clamp and cut the cord between
                the clamps. \n\n
            \t D.	To facilitate delivery of the upper shoulder, gently guide the head downward. Support and
                lift the head and neck slightly to deliver the lower shoulder. \n\n
            \t E.	The rest of the infant should deliver quickly with one contraction. Firmly grasp the infant
                as it emerges. Baby will be wet and slippery. \n\n
            \t F.	Keep infant level with perineum until the cord stops pulsating and is double clamped and
                cut. Proceed to Newborn And Post-Partum Care Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t G.	If able, mother may hold infant on chest / abdomen during transport.
    </string>

    <!--param_childbirth complications-->
    <string name="title_activity_childbirth_complications">Childbirth Complications</string>
    <string name="parameter_childbirtch_complications_header">
        <b><u>CHILDBIRTH COMPLICATIONS</u></b> \n\n
        <b>TRANSPORT AS SOON AS POSSIBLE – \n
            DO NOT DELAY ON SCENE</b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_childbirtch_complications">
        <b>I.	BREECH BIRTH</b> \n\n
            \t •<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •<b>Never attempt to pull the infant from the vagina.</b> \n\n
            \t •	As soon as the legs are delivered, support the baby\'s body wrapped in a towel. \n\n
            \t •	After the shoulders are delivered, if the neonate is face down, gently elevate the legs and
                trunk to facilitate delivery of the head. \n\n
            \t •	Head should deliver in 30 seconds. If NOT, reach two sterile gloved fingers into vagina to
                locate baby\'s mouth. Push vaginal wall away from baby\'s mouth to form an airway. \n\n
            \t •	Apply gentle pressure to the fundus. If head does NOT deliver in 2 minutes, keep your fingers
                in place to maintain the airway. \n\n
        <b>II.	PROLAPSED CORD</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Elevate mother\'s hips. \n\n
            \t •	Place sterile gloved hand into vagina between pubic bone and presenting part with cord between
                two fingers to monitor cord pulsations and exert counter-pressure on presenting part. \n\n
            \t •	Cover exposed cord with moist dressing and keep warm. \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_post partum care-->
    <string name="title_activity_post_partum">Post Partum</string>
    <string name="parameter_post_partum_header"><b><u>POST-PARTUM CARE</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_post_partum">
        <b>TRANSPORT AS SOON AS POSSIBLE, EVEN IF PLACENTA HAS NOT DELIVERED \n\n</b>
        I.	The placenta should deliver in 20-30 minutes. If delivered, collect in plastic bag. Do not pull
            on cord to facilitate delivery of the placenta. \n\n
        II.	If perineum torn and bleeding apply direct pressure with sanitary pads and have patient bring
            her legs together. \n\n
        III.	If significant blood loss or signs of hypo-perfusion: \n\n
            \t •	<b>Fluid boluses</b> in increments of 250 ml, to titrate systolic BP >90 mm Hg. \n
            \t •	Gently massage abdomen over uterus, until uterus is firm. \n
        IV.	If altered sensorium, signs of hypo-perfusion despite above, refer to the Shock
            <i>Clinical Care Guideline</i> and/or the <i>Altered Mental Status Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_prenatal emergencies-->
    <string name="title_activity_prenatal_emergencies">Prenatal Emergencies</string>
    <string name="parameter_prenatal_emergencies_header"><b><u>PRENATAL EMERGENCIES</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_prenatal_emergencies">
        <b>I.	PREGNANCY INDUCED HYPERTENSION</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	Gentle handling. Minimize CNS stimulation. \n\n
            \t •	Position patient on left side or raise right side of backboard approximately 30 degrees. \n\n
            \t •	If seizure occurs, refer to ECLAMPSIA (below). \n\n
            \t •	Treat hypertension per <i>Hypertensive Crisis Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
        <b>II.	PRE–ECLAMPSIA</b> \n\n
            \t •	Signs and Symptoms may include: headache dizziness, vomiting/diarrhea, vision changes,
                and BP greater than 140/90 \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	Closely observe patient for possibility of seizure activity (CNS, Disturbances, and Auras). \n\n
            \t •	Physician\'s Orders: Magnesium Sulfate - 5 Grams in 250 ml of D5W infused over 20 minutes. \n\n
        <b>III.	ECLAMPSIA</b> \n\n
            \t •	Any Signs and Symptoms associated with Pre-Eclampsia and seizure activity, and an even
                higher Blood pressure \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Magnesium Sulfate:</b> 5 Grams in 250 ml of D5W infused over 20 minutes. For
                Inter-facility Transports with an established Magnesium Sulfate drip, continue the
                infusion rate per the transferring facility’s order. \n\n
            \t •	Seizures refractory to Magnesium Sulfate: \n\n
            \t •	<b>Midazolam </b>5 mg IM/IVP or Intra-nasal with max does of 10 mg \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_trauma in pregnancy-->
    <string name="title_activity_trauma_in_pregnancy">TraumaInPregnancyActivity</string>
    <string name="parameter_trauma_pregnancy_header"><b><u>TRAUMA IN PREGNANCY</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_trauma_pregnancy">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical \trauma Care</b> \n\n
        II.	Check for uterine contractions, vaginal bleeding, and / or leaking amniotic fluid.
            Assess for fetal movements. \n\n
        III.	Raise right side of backboard approximately 30 degrees, unless increased patient
            distress / pain, \n\n
        IV.	If hypotension / shock present, refer to Shock Clinical Care Guideline \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_trauma_pregnancy_end">
        <b>MOST COMMON CAUSE OF FETAL DEATH IS MATERNAL DEATH</b> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_vaginal bleeding-->
    <string name="title_activity_vaginal_bleeding">Vaginal Bleeding</string>
    <string name="parameter_vaginal_bleeding_header"><b><u>VAGINAL BLEEDING</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_vaginal_bleeding">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
        II.	Determine date of Last Menstrual Period (LMP). Note passage of clots or tissue and save
            for analysis. DO NOT perform vaginal examination. \n\n
        III.	<b>Unknown pregnancy status and/or LMP, and/or known pregnancy in first 6 months:</b> \n\n
            \t •	Place patient in left lateral recumbent position. \n\n
            \t •	If hypotensive, refer to Shock Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	If in active labor, refer to Childbirth (Emergency) Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
        IV.	<b>Third trimester bleeding:</b> \n\n
            \t •<b>IV:</b> Establish 2 large bore IV lines with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	Place patient in left lateral recumbent position. \n\n
            \t •	If hypotensive, refer to Shock Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	If in active labor, refer to <i>Childbirth (Emergency) Clinical Care Guideline.</i> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_pediatric asystole / pea-->
    <string name="title_activity_pediatric_asystole">Pediatric Asystole</string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_asystole_header"><b><u>PEDIATRIC ASYSTOLE / PEA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_asystole">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Length-Based Tape:</b> measure child to determine weight and color zone. Select
                RESUSCITATION medication dosages and equipment as indicated by color zone on the
                Length-Based Tape. If Length-Based Tape not available, calculate dosages using weight-based
                dosages listed below. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Cardiac Arrest Management:</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	Assess patient using Primary ABCD Survey and perform appropriate action following
                    American Heart Association (AHA) CPR Guidelines. \n
                \t\t ii.	Follow <i>End of Life Administrative Policy</i>, as necessary. \n
                \t\t iii.	<b>If arrest &gt; 4 minutes:</b> perform 2 minutes of CPR prior to assessing
                    rhythm. \n
                \t\t iv.	<b>If arrest &lt; 4 minutes or witnessed:</b> assess rhythm. \n
                \t\t v.	Reassess rhythm after every 2 minute period of CPR; assess radial pulse if organized
                    rhythm, do not exceed 10 seconds. If no radial pulse or unsure, resume CPR. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Resuscitation:</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n
                \t\t ii.	<b>Epinephrine</b> 1:10,000: 0.01 mg/kg IV/IO. Repeat every 3-5 minutes of
                    continued arrest. \n
                \t\t iii.	<b>Advanced Airway:</b> endotracheal intubation. \n
                \t\t iv.	<b>Contributing Factors:</b> search for and treat 6 Hs &amp; 6 Ts. \n\n
            \t •	If return of spontaneous circulation and/or breathing, follow Post Resuscitation Management
                Clinical Care Guideline.
    </string>

    <!--param_pediatric bradycardia-->
    <string name="title_activity_pediatric_bradycardia">Pediatric Bradycardia</string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_brady_header"><b><u>PEDIATRIC BRADYCARDIA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_brady">
        <b>BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t I.	<b>Initial Medical Care:</b> assess and support ABCs as needed. \n\n
            \t II.	<b>Length-Based Tape:</b> measure child to determine weight and color zone.
                Medication dosages listed on the Length-Based Tape are based upon resuscitation,
                not bradycardia management. Calculate dosages using weight-based dosages. \n\n
            \t III.	<b>Cardiopulmonary Support:</b> provide if HR &lt; 80 with inadequate perfusion. Start
                with Oxygen and progressing to BVM and/or CPR if limited or no response to therapy after
                30-60 seconds. \n\n
                \t\t  •	<b>Oxygen:</b> high flow via blow-by or pediatric mask. \n
                \t\t •	<b>BVMR:</b> ventilation rate of 20 breaths/min. If poor perfusion persists despite
                    aggressive oxygenation. \n
                \t\t •	<b>CPR:</b> perform if HR &lt; 60 with poor perfusion despite aggressive oxygenation
                    and ventilation. \n\n
        <b>ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t I.	<b>Persistent Symptomatic Bradycardia:</b> \n\n
                \t\t •	<b>Contributing Factors:</b> search for and treat 6 H\'s &amp; 5 T\'s \n
                    \t\t\t i.	<b>Fluid boluses for hypovolemia should be calculated using LBT</b> \n
                \t\t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n
                \t\t •	<b>Epinephrine</b> 1:10,000: 0.01 mg/kg IV/10, repeat every 3-5 minutes of continued
                    bradycardia Indications: consider if refractory to aggressive BASIC CARE measures. \n
                \t\t •	<b>Atropine Sulfate</b>: 0.02 mg/kg IV/IO, repeat every 3-5 minutes (min dose of 0.1mg;
                    max total dose 1 mg). Indications: consider if refractory to aggressive BASIC CARE and if
                    increased vagal tone or primary AV block. \n
                \t\t •	<b>Physician Consult:</b> Contact Medical Control for alternative treatments \n\n
                \t\t\t (ex. Transcutaneous Pacing) if above measures are unsuccessful. \n
    </string>

    <!--param_pediatric esophageal foreign body obstruction-->
    <string name="title_activity_pediatric_fbo">Pediatric EFBO</string>
    <string name="parameter_pedi_esophageal_obstruction_header"><b><u>PEDIATRIC ESOPHAGEAL FOREIGN
        BODY OBSTRUCTION</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_pedi_esophageal_obstruction">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical Care</b> \n\n
        II.	If airway obstruction present, refer to <i>Foreign Body Airway Obstruction Clinical Care
        Guideline.</i> \b\b \n\n
        III.	<b>Airway Maneuvers</b> \n\n
            \t •	Protect against aspiration. \n
            \t  •	<b>Oxygen:</b> blow-by; if patient hypoxic apply appropriate oxygen adjunct with appropriate liter flow. \n
            \t  •	<b>Cardiac Monitor</b> \n
            \t  •	<b>Capnography:</b> apply nasal cannula Filter Line. \n\n
        IV.	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
        V.	Place patient in position of comfort. \n\n
        VI.	Encourage coughing. \n\n
        VII.	<b>Glucagon:</b> 0.1 mg IVP. May repeat in 5 minutes (maximum total dose 1 mg).
            \t •	Pt must be transported after glucagon administration \n\n
    </string>

    <!--para_pediatric febrile emergency -->
    <string name="title_activity_pediatric_febrile_emergency">Pediatric Febrile </string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_febrile_header"><b><u>PEDIATRIC FEBRILE EMERGENCY</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_febrile">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care:</b> assess and support ABCs as needed. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Length-Based Tape:</b> measure child to determine weight and color zone. Medication
                dosages listed on the Length-Based Tape are based upon resuscitation. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Temperature Assessment:</b> 1020 F or higher, initiate <b>Cooling and Advanced Care.</b> \n\n
            \t •<b>Cooling: </b>	move patient to cool environment. Remove clothing, if appropriate, and sponge
                patient with tepid water. Do not chill patient too rapidly as this may cause shivering and
                increased heat production \n\n
            \t •	Vomiting / aspiration precautions \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	IV: Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	Contributing Factors: search for and treat possible contributing factors. Fluid boluses for h
                ypovolemia should be calculated using LBT \n\n
            \t •	Blood Glucose Level: If blood glucose level &lt; 60, refer to Hypoglycemia &amp; Hyperglycemia
                Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	Observe patient’s sensorium and airway during postictal period. Consider etiology and refer
                to Altered Mental Status Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	Place nothing in mouth during seizure. \n\n
        <b>III.	  Midazolam</b> 0.1 mg/kg IVP, IM or Intra-nasal with max does of 5 mg \n\n
        <b>IV.	   Physician Orders:</b> Contact Medical Control if seizure activity continues. \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_pediatric infectious upper airway obstruction -->
    <string name="title_activity_pediatric_infectios">Pediatric Infectios</string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_infectious_header">
        <b><u>PEDIATRIC INFECTIOUS UPPER AIRWAY OBSTRUCTION</u></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_infectious">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Length-Based Tape:</b> measure child to determine weight and color zone.
                Select equipment as indicated by color zone on the Length-Based Tape.  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care:</b> assess and support ABCs as needed. Significant attempts
                should be made to keep child calm at all times; including allowing parents close contact
                with patient during transport.  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Oxygen:</b> via Pediatric mask or "blow-by" technique. If respiratory failure is imminent,
                use BVMR and ventilate with Oxygen @ 15 LPM.  \n\n
        <b>II.	 ADVANCED CARE</b>  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Capnography:</b> apply nasal cannula Filter Line.  \n\n
        <b>Supportive Care:</b>  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Humidified Oxygen:</b> with 3 ml of NS via blow-by.  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Albuterol:</b> 2.5 mg via blow-by, if effective may repeat x 2. <i>Indications:</i>
                bronchial constriction and/or wheezing.  \n\n
            \t •	If no response, <b>Albuterol</b> 2.5 mg and <b>Atrovent</b>0.5 mg combined via updraft
                blow-by.  \n\n
        <b>Impending Respiratory Failure:</b>  \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV of NS KVO.  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Solu-Medrol:</b> 2 mg/kg IV (max total dose 125 mg). Indications: moderate to severe
                obstruction refractory to beta-agonists.  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Advanced Airway:</b> Endotracheal tube. Do not attempt aggressive airway intervention
                unless airway becomes obstructed. Use an ET tube one size smaller than the recommended size
                according to the Length-Based Tape. If the patient is physiologically difficult to intubate
                (severe anxiety, etc.) refer to Difficult Airway - Facilitated Intubation Guideline.  \n\n
            \t •	<b>Needle Cricothyrotomy Indications:</b> Unable to ventilate effectively after above
                attempts.  \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_pediatric tachycardia-->
    <string name="title_activity_pediatric_tachycardia">Pediatric Tachycardia</string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_tachycardia_header"><b><u>PEDIATRIC TACHYCARDIA</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_tachycardia">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical Care.</b> Place patient in their position of comfort. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Length-Based Tape:</b> measure child to determine weight and color zone. Select
                antiarrhythmic dosages and equipment as indicated by color zone on the Length-Based Tape.
                If Length-Based Tape not available, calculate dosages using weight-based dosages listed
                below. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Treat Underlying Cause:</b> assess and treat suspected cause if sinus tachycardia
                (See Notes). \n\n
            \t •	<b>Vagal Maneuvers:</b> perform Valsalva maneuver or apply cool moisture to face. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Antiarrhythmic Agents:</b> \n\n
                \t\t i.	<b>Adenosine:</b> first dose of 0.1 mg/kg Rapid IVP (maximum 1st dose of 6 mg). If
                    no conversion, second dose: 0.2 mg/kg Rapid IVP (maximum 2nd dose of 12 mg).
                    <u>Indications:</u> stable patients with narrow-complex tachycardia. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	<b>Amiodarone:</b> 5 mg/kg IV drip (bolus over 20 minutes) (max single dose of
                    300 mg) \n\n
                    <u>Indications:</u> stable patients with wide-complex tachycardia. \n\n
                \t\t iii.	Physician\’s Consult: contact Medical Control for alternative treatments if above
                    antiarrhythmic agents are unsuccessful in rhythm conversion or rate control. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Synchronized Cardioversion:</b> 1 J/kg \n\n
                \t\t <u>Indications:</u> unstable patients with inadequate perfusion. \n\n
                \t\t i.	Consider pre-medication with Midazolam: 0.1 mg/kg IV or Intra-nasal, repeat every
                    3-5 minutes until adequate relaxation / sedation is achieved prior to procedure
                    (max total dosage 4 mg). Use Midazolam with caution in the presence of hypotension. \n\n
                \t\t ii.	If rhythm does not convert, escalate energy level to 2 J/kg for Subsequent
                    SYNCHRONIZED CARDIOVERSIONS \n\n
                \t\t iii.	If delays in synchronization occur and clinical condition is critical, proceed
                    immediately to unsynchronized shocks i.e. defibrillation \n\n
        <b><u>NOTES:</u></b> \n\n
        1.	Sinus tachycardia: p-waves present and normal, usually has variable RR intervals (varies during
            respirations and agitation), and constant PR interval.
    </string>

    <string name="parameter_pediatric_tachycardia_chart1">
        Infants:	HR usually &lt; 220 bpm. \n
        Children:	HR usually &lt; 180 bpm.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_tachycardia_note2">
        2.	SVT or narrow-complex tachycardia: p-waves absent / abnormal, RR intervals not variable, and
        history of abrupt rate changes.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_tachycardia_chart2">
        Infants:	HR usually &gt; 220 bpm. \n
        Children:	HR usually &gt; 180 bpm.
    </string>

    <!--param_PEDIATRIC V-FIB & PULSELESS V-TACH-->
    <string name="title_activity_pediatric_vfib">Pediatric Vfib</string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_vfib_header"><b><u>PEDIATRIC V-FIB &amp; PULSELESS V-TACH</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_pediatric_vfib">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Length-Based Tape:</b> measure child to determine weight and color zone. Select
                RESUSCITATION medication dosages and equipment as indicated by color zone on the Length-Based
                Tape. If Length-Based Tape not available, calculate dosages using weight-based dosages. \n\n
        <b>Cardiac Arrest Management:</b>
            \t •	Assess patient using Primary ABCD Survey and perform appropriate action following American
                Heart Association (AHA) CPR Guidelines. \n\n
            \t •	If using an AED, follow the manufacturer\'s prompts for cardiac arrest management (use
                pediatric AED system if available for children 1 to 8 years of age). \n\n
            \t •	Follow <i>End Of Life Administrative Policy</i>, as necessary. \n\n
            \t •	<b>If arrest &gt; 4 minutes:</b> perform 2 minutes of CPR prior to assessing rhythm. \n\n
            \t •	<b>If arrest &lt; 4-minutes or witnessed:</b> assess rhythm. \n\n
            \t •<b>Defibrillation:</b>	 2 J / kg x 1 shock. \n\n
                \t\t\t\t i.	<b>Non-organized rhythm:</b> start CPR. \n\n
                \t\t\t\t ii. <b>Organized rhythm:</b> check pulse &lt; 10 seconds. If no radial pulse or
                    unsure, perform 2 minutes of CPR and then reassess. \n\n
            \t •	Reassess rhythm after every 2-minute period of CPR. \n\n
            \t •	If shock-able rhythm persists, use 4 J / kg for subsequent shocks. \n\n
            \t •	Treatment Sequence: Prepare next drug prior to rhythm check. Administer drug during CPR,
                as soon as possible after the rhythm check confirms VF/pulseless VT. Do not delay shock.
                Continue CPR while drugs are prepared and administered and defibrillator is charging.
                Ideally, chest compressions should be interrupted only for ventilation (until advanced
                airway placed), rhythm check, and shock delivery \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
        <b>Resuscitation:</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV/IO of NS KVO. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Epinephrine</b> 1:10,000: 0.01 mg/kg IV/10. Repeat every 3-5 minutes of continued arrest. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Antiarrhythmic Agents:</b> repeated every 3-5 minutes of continued arrest \n\n
                \t\t i.	<b>Amiodarone:</b> 5 mg/kg IV/IO, repeat x 2 doses (max single dose of 300 mg) \n\n
                \t\t ii.	<b>Magnesium Sulfate:</b> 50 mg/kg slow IVP/IO over 5 minutes mixed in 10 ml \n\n
                    NS (maximum total dose 2 grams). <i>Indications:</i> torsades de pointes \n\n
            \t •	Advanced Airway \n\n
            \t •	Contributing Factors: search for and treat 6 H\'s &amp; 5 T\'s. If hypovolemia known or
                suspected, administer fluid boluses as calculated by Length-Based Tape (20 ml/kg).
                Max 3 boluses \n\n
        <b>Post-resuscitation Maintenance Therapy:</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Amiodarone:</b> 5 mg/kg IV/IO drip over 20 minutes (maximum single dose 300 mg)
                Indications: If rhythm converts prior to antiarrhythmic agent. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Midazolam:</b> 0.1 mg/kg IV/IO or Intra-nasal, repeat every 5 minutes (maximum total
                dose 4 mg) (6). <u>Indications:</u> combative post resuscitation patients. Use Midazolam with
                caution in the presence or hypotension. \n\n
        III.	Refer to <i>Post-resuscitation Management Clinical Care Guideline</i> \n\n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_NEWBORN CARE-->
    <string name="title_activity_newborn">Newborn Care</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_header"><b><u>NEWBORN CARE</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn">
        I.	.Deliver infant according to <i>Childbirth (Emergency) Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n
            \t •	Record TIME of delivery. \n
            \t •	Record APGAR score at 1 and 5 minutes. \n\n
        II.	Continue to suction mouth <b>FIRST</b>, then nose of infant with bulb syringe. <b>Meconium-stained
            infants should not be stimulated to breathe until suctioning has occurred</b>: \n
            \t •	Suction <u>only</u> upon delivery of the head <u>PRIOR</u> to delivery of the baby. \n
            \t •	After delivery, INTUBATE infant and apply suction to the lumen of the ETT while withdrawing
                from the trachea. Following intubation, confirm proper tube placement by auscultating the
                gastric area and the lungs bilaterally, and noting positive change on the end-tidal CO2
                detector. \n\n
        III.	Continually assess respiratory rate.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_iv">
        IV.	Assess heart rate.\n\n
            \t •	If the heart rate is &lt; 100 beats per minute, positive-pressure ventilations with
                100\u0025 oxygen should be initiated immediately. \n
            \t •	If the heart rate is &lt; 60 beats per minute or 60 to 80 beats per minute and not
                increasing rapidly despite effective ventilation with 100\u0025 oxygen, <b><u>CHEST
                COMPRESSIONS  SHOULD BE INITIATED.</u></b> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--newborn table1-->
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tb1r1c1">
        <b>If Respirations Adequate / Pt Crying:</b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tb1r1c2">
        <b>If Respirations Shallow, Slow, Or Absent:</b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tb1r2c1">
        Place infant on side in Trendelenburg position.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tb1r2c2">
        Assist ventilations with OXYGEN @ 100/u0025 via BVM.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tb1r3c1">
        Assess color and provide OXYGEN @ 100/u0025 via NRB mask if central cyanosis present.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tb1r3c2">
        If respirations improve, provide OXYGEN @ 100/u0025 via NRB mask.
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tb1r4c1">
        If respirations improve, administer "blow-by" OXYGEN.
    </string>

    <!--newborn table2-->
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r1c1">SIGN</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r1c2">0</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r1c3">1</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r1c4">2</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r2c1">Appearance</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r2c2">Pale / blue</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r2c3">Pink body, blue extremities</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r2c4">Pink body, pink extremities</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r3c1">Pulse</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r3c2">Absent</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r3c3">Less than 100</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r3c4">100 or greater</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r4c1">Grimace</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r4c2">No response</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r4c3">Grimace</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r4c4">Cough, sneeze</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r5c1">Activity</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r5c2">Limp</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r5c3">Some flexion</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r5c4">Action</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r6c1">Respiratory effort</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r6c2">Absent</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r6c3">Slow, irregular</string>
    <string name="parameter_newborn_tbl2r6c4">Strong crying</string>

    <!--param_ANIMAL BITES & STINGS-->
    <string name="title_activity_animal_bite">Animal Bite/Sting</string>
    <string name="parameter_animal_bite_header"><b><u>ANIMAL BITES &amp; STINGS</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_animal_bite">
        <b>I.	VENOMUS/POISONOUS</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical / Trauma Care.</b> Contact law enforcement. \n\n
            \t •	Irrigate and cleanse wound with saline. \n\n
            \t •	Assess degree of bite or sting by measuring bite / sting marks. Outline edematous, erythemic and
                ecchymotic areas with pen, and note time. \n\n
            \t •	Apply constricting band if ETA to initial receiving facility is &gt; 20 minutes. Apply
                constricting band proximal to wound if insect or snake bite / sting shows signs of increasing
                reaction. Ensure constricting band does not impede arterial blood flow. \n\n
            \t •	Keep patient supine and calm. Immobilize affected part. Remove distal jewelry. \n\n
            \t •	Remove stingers; if present, taking care to avoid compression. \n\n
            \t •	Identify animal that caused bite or sting. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Do not apply ice or cold pack to snake bites or marine stings</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Bring the dead animal to the hospital, if able. Do not try to catch the animal if it is
                still alive.</b> \n\n
        <b>II.	TRAUMATIC</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical / Trauma Care.</b> \n\n
            \t •	Cleanse area around wounds. \n\n
            \t •	Dry sterile dressing to wounds. \n\n
            \t •	Treat per applicable Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n

        <b><u>NOTES</u></b>
        <b>Contact the American Association of Poison Control Centers</b>, through the Communications
        Center or by calling <b>1-800-222-1222</b>, to obtain information regarding the initial stabilization
        and management of the exposure. <b>The American Association of Poison Control Centers</b> will
        assume responsibility and provide home management and follow-up per their standard
        operating protocols as required by Florida Statutes \n\n
        <b>Patients presenting with signs and symptoms consistent with anaphylaxis must be treated with the
            appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline.</i></b> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_BURNS-->
    <string name="title_activity_burns">BurnsActivity</string>
    <string name="parameter_burns_header"><b><u>BURNS</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_burns">
        <b><u>INHALATION BURNS</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Note presence of wheezing, hoarseness, stridor, carbonaceous sputum / cough,
                singed nasal hair, eyebrows / lashes or respiratory distress. \n\n
            \t •	<b>BVMR:</b> Assist ventilations if respiratory insufficiency is evident. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached \n\n
            \t •	<b>Intubation:</b> Consider early intubation if the above respiratory involvement
                signs are present. If early intubation is warranted or the patient is physiologically
                difficult to intubate (severe anxiety, etc.), refer to Difficult Airway-Facilitated
                Intubation Guideline for sedation. \n\n
        <b><u>ELECTRICAL BURNS</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Establish scene safety. Have electrical source turned off. Immobilize as indicated. \n\n
            \t •	Assess for entry and exit wounds. Assess neurovascular status of affected part. \n\n
            \t •	Cover wounds with dry sterile dressings (cooling not necessary). \n\n
            \t •	Spinal immobilization if high voltage electrical injuries (>1000 Volts, excluding Taser) \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached \n\n
            \t •	Assess ECG for arrhythmias and refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
            \t •	Refer to <i>Pain Management Clinical Care Guideline</i>. \n\n
        <b><u>CHEMICAL BURNS</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Primary decontamination listed below should be performed prior to transport and in
                coordination with Hazmat Guideline</b> \n\n
            \t •	If powdered chemical, brush away excess. Remove clothing if possible and place in red
                biohazard bag (do not transport the bag in the passenger/patient compartment). \n\n
            \t •	Irrigate with copious amounts of water or saline ASAP and during transport. \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	Refer to <i>Pain Management Clinical Care Guideline.</i> \n\n
        <b><u>THERMAL BURNS</u></b> \n\n
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Remove or cool heat source if present (tar, clothing) \n\n
            \t •	Apply cool compress dressings on minor burns with sterile saline (do not use ice packs). \n\n
            \t •	Apply dry, sterile burn sheet on: \n\n
                \t\t i.	2° burns greater than 15% of Body Surface Area \n
                \t\t ii.	3° burns \n\n
        <b>II.	ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached. \n\n
            \t •	Refer to <i>Pain Management Clinical Care Guideline</i> \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_CHEST INJURIES-->
    <string name="title_activity_chest_injury">Chest Injury</string>
    <string name="parameter_chest_injury_header"><b><u>CHEST INJURY</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_chest_injury">
        <b>I.	SUCKING CHEST WOUND/OPEN PNEUMOTHORAX</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical/Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Apply occlusive dressing taped on three sides to create flutter valve. \n\n
            \t •	If patient deteriorates, remove dressing temporarily to allow air to escape. \n\n
        <b>II.	TENSION PNEUMOTHORAX</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical/Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached \n\n
            \t •	Suspect when patient presents with severe respiratory distress, hypotension, distended
                neck veins, absent breath sounds on the involved side, and/or tracheal deviation. Also
                suspect when marked resistance is met while assisting respirations. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Pleural Decompression on the affected side.</b> \n\n
        <b>III.	PERICARDIAL TAMPONADE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical/Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached \n\n
            \t •	Suspect when patient presents with hypotension, distended neck veins, muffled heart tones
                and good breath sounds bilaterally, or penetrating chest injuries between the right
                midclavicular line and the left midaxillary line. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Fluid Bolus:</b> 250 ml increments of NS while transporting (maximum total infusion
                1 liter). \n\n
        <b>IV.	FLAIL SEGMENT</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical/Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Splint/support</b> flail segment with soft splinting material \n\n
            \t •	Assess for ventilatory compromise. \n\n
            \t •	If patient deteriorates, assess for possible pneumothorax. \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV with NS lock attached \n\n
    </string>

    <!--param_CRUSH INJURY / ENTRAPMENT-->
    <string name="title_activity_crush">Crush / Entrapment</string>
    <string name="parameter_crush_header"><b><u>CRUSH INJURY / ENTRAPMENT</u></b></string>
    <string name="parameter_crush">
        <b>I.	BASIC CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	<b>Initial Medical/Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Keep patient warm \n\n
            \t •	<b>Oxygen:</b> 15 LPM NRB \n\n
        <b>II.	 ADVANCED CARE</b> \n\n
            \t •	Cardiac monitor \n\n
            \t •	<b>Pulse Oximetry and Capnography:</b> Apply capnography and monitor respiratory drive. \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV:</b> Establish an IV of NS KVO \n\n
            \t •	<b>Fluid bolus</b> in 250 ml increments, re-evaluating every 250 ml. Titrate systolic BP
                &gt; 100 mm Hg. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Pain Management:</b> refer to Pain Management Clinical Care Guideline. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Ondansetron:</b> 4 mg slow IVP over 2 minutes for nausea and vomiting \n\n
        <b>III.	Physician’s Consult:</b> For delayed extrications where one or more extremities is involved
                and circulation is compromised contact Medical Control for: \n\n
            \t •	<b>IV fluids</b> of 1000 ml, followed by 500 ml/hr drip. \n\n
            \t •	<b>Sodium Bicarbonate:</b>50 mEq IVP. \n\n
            \t •	Constricting bands on affected extremities prior to release. \n\n

    </string>

    <!--param_DECOMPRESSION SICKNESS & DYSBARISM-->
    <string name="title_activity_decompression">Decompression Sickness</string>
    <string name="parameter_decompression_header">
        <b><u>DECOMPRESSION SICKNESS &amp; DYSBARISM</u></b> \n\n\n
        <b><u>SIGNS AND SYMPTOMS:</u></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_decompression">
                    \t\t\t •	Onset usually within 1 - 3 hours after scuba diving. \n
                    \t\t\t •	Severe, throbbing pain involving the muscles, joints, and abdomen. \n
                    \t\t\t •	Pruritus and mottling of the skin. \n
                    \t\t\t •	Patients with a severe reaction will have CNS and / or respiratory difficulties. \n\n
        <b>I.	Initial Medical/Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Position and transport patient in left lateral, head down position. Keep patient warm. \n\n
        <b>II.	Transport Destination:</b> Determine and coordinate with the Communications Center for
            transport arrangements to the closest hyperbaric chamber. \n\n
            \t •	If the patient is exhibiting altered mental status, the paramedic should immediately coordinate
                with the Communications Center and Receiving facility for possible transport arrangements to the
                closest Hyperbaric Chamber: \n\n
                \t\t 	UF Health Shands Gainesville \n\n
                \t\t 	Florida Hospital Orlando \n\n
        III.	If other significant injuries exist, follow <i>Trauma Transport Protocol or appropriate
            Clinical Care Guideline.</i>
    </string>
    <!--param_DROWNING & NEAR DROWNING-->
    <string name="title_activity_drowning">DrowningActivity</string>
    <string name="parameter_drowning_header">
        <b><u>DROWNING &amp; NEAR DROWNING</u></b>
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_drowning">
        I.	<b>Initial Medical/Trauma Care</b> \n\n
            \t •	Care should begin in the water, if appropriate.
        II.	<b>Dry patient:</b> remove wet clothing and protect patient against heat loss and wind chill.
        Completely dry patient and cover patient with insulated blanket. \n\n
        III.	If arrhythmias are present, refer to appropriate <i>Clinical Care Guideline.</i> \n\n
        IV.	If patient is hypothermic, refer to Environmental <i>Cold Emergencies Clinical Care
            Guideline.</i> 
    </string>
    <string name="parameter_drowning_end"> \n\n
        ADULT (&gt; 15 years old) near drowning should be considered a medical call unless trauma is
            suspected. These medical patients should be transported by ground to an initial receiving
            facility. If trauma is evident, transport to a trauma center via air or ground transport per
            Trauma Transport Protocol Administrative Policy. \n\n
        PEDIATRIC (&lt; 15 years old) near drowning should be transported to a trauma center, whether
            the mechanism was trauma or medical via air or ground transport per Trauma Transport Protocol
            Administrative Policy. \n\n
    </string>
</resources>
